<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mesenchymal Stem Cells | Oswestry Keele Orthopaedic Research group - OsKOR</title>
    <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/tag/mesenchymal-stem-cells/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://oskor.netlify.app/tag/mesenchymal-stem-cells/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Mesenchymal Stem Cells</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://oskor.netlify.app/media/logo_hu0e35ae0aaba2517cccb2b0d7ca3e2f28_296151_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url>
      <title>Mesenchymal Stem Cells</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/tag/mesenchymal-stem-cells/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Umbilical Cord-Derived Mesenchymal Stromal Cells Reduce Radiographic Osteoarthritis in an Ovine Model</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/human-umbilical-cord-derived-mesenchymal-stromal-cells-reduce-radiographic-osteoarthritis-in-an-ovine-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/human-umbilical-cord-derived-mesenchymal-stromal-cells-reduce-radiographic-osteoarthritis-in-an-ovine-model/</guid>
      <description>


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Therapeutic Effects of Hypoxic and Pro-Inflammatory Priming of Mesenchymal Stem Cell-Derived Extracellular Vesicles in Inflammatory Arthritis</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/therapeutic-effects-of-hypoxic-and-pro-inflammatory-priming-of-mesenchymal-stem-cell-derived-extracellular-vesicles-in-inflammatory-arthritis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/therapeutic-effects-of-hypoxic-and-pro-inflammatory-priming-of-mesenchymal-stem-cell-derived-extracellular-vesicles-in-inflammatory-arthritis/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/therapeutic-effects-of-hypoxic-and-pro-inflammatory-priming-of-mesenchymal-stem-cell-derived-extracellular-vesicles-in-inflammatory-arthritis/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cell therapy for cartilage repair</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/cell-therapy-for-cartilage-repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/cell-therapy-for-cartilage-repair/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/cell-therapy-for-cartilage-repair/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSCs-Derived Extracellular Vesicles Attenuate Disease Severity in Inflammatory Arthritis</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/mscs-evs-inlfamm-arthritis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/mscs-evs-inlfamm-arthritis/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Rheumatoid arthritis is a painful autoimmune disorder characterised by synovial inflammation that leads to progressive destruction of articular cartilage.
There is no cure for RA and life expectancy of sufferers may be reduced by up to 18 years. For that reason, it is vital to develop a new and more effective therapy for RA.
Mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) possess anti-inflammatory and immunosuppressive properties and function predominantly through paracrine mechanisms, via growth factors, cytokines, chemokines and bioactive, membrane-bound extracellular vesicles (EVs) found in mesenchymal stem cell conditioned medium (CM-MSC).
Our previous project demonstrated that CM-MSC reduces swelling and cartilage destruction through modulation of the immune response in a murine model of inflammatory arthritis.
This current study is assessing the contribution of extracellular vesicles to this therapeutic outcome, and examining how the culture microenvironment of MSCs can be manipulated to enhance their therapeutic effectiveness.
Extracellular vesicles are applied as a treatment in our pre-clinical model of experimental arthritis, looking at their effects on inflammation, histological outcomes of disease progression and T cell polarisation towards either pro- or anti-inflammatory cell types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stem cells isolated from human bone marrow aspirate were used to derive extracellular vesicles. Following the application of vesicles, knee joint swelling significantly reduced at both 24 and 48 hours after treatment in our pre-clinical model (Figure 1). Reductions were highly significant in comparison to control animals where knee joints continued to swell in the absence of extracellular vesicles.
Histological analysis reviled improved scores for cartilage and arthritis index (Figure 2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The significant reduction in joint swelling following EVs treatment demonstrates their effectiveness as a new therapeutic intervention.
Further investigation will identify the mechanisms involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:block;&#34; id=&#34;fig:figures&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;figure1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Therapeutic outcomes in an inflammatory arthritis model (AIA). Alleviation of joint swelling as a measure of therapeutic efficacy following EV treatments show significant influence of EVs compared to controls at day 2 and day 3 after arthritis induction, normalised to peak swelling.&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: Therapeutic outcomes in an inflammatory arthritis model (AIA). Alleviation of joint swelling as a measure of therapeutic efficacy following EV treatments show significant influence of EVs compared to controls at day 2 and day 3 after arthritis induction, normalised to peak swelling.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:block;&#34; id=&#34;fig:fig2&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;Examination of histological signs of arthritis pathogenesis following EV treatment shows significant therapeutic effects of EVs sourced from normoxic and pro-inflammatory pre-conditioned MSC cultures.&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 2: Examination of histological signs of arthritis pathogenesis following EV treatment shows significant therapeutic effects of EVs sourced from normoxic and pro-inflammatory pre-conditioned MSC cultures.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syndecan-3 plays a role in MSC adhesion and efficacy in an in vivo model of inflammatory arthritis</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/syndecan-3-regulates-msc-adhesion-erk-and-akt-signaling-in-vitro-and-its-deletion-enhances-msc-efficacy-in-a-model-of-inflammatory-arthritis-in-vivo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/syndecan-3-regulates-msc-adhesion-erk-and-akt-signaling-in-vitro-and-its-deletion-enhances-msc-efficacy-in-a-model-of-inflammatory-arthritis-in-vivo/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Inflammation is a central feature of rheumatoid arthritis that affects around 1% of the population and can result in disability and morbidity.
The immunomodulatory effects of bone marrow derived mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) has been widely studied and the recent observations that syndecan-3 (SDC3) is selectively pro-inflammatory in the joint led us to hypothesise that SDC3 might play an important role in MSC biology.
MSCs isolated from bone marrow of wild type and Sdc3-/- mice were used to assess immunophenotype, differentiation, adhesion and migration properties and cell signalling pathways.
While both cell types show similar differentiation potential and forward scatter values, the cell complexity in wild type MSCs was significantly higher than in Sdc3-/- cells and was accompanied by lower spread surface area.
Moreover, Sdc3-/- MSCs adhered more rapidly to collagen type I and showed a dramatic increase in AKT phosphorylation, accompanied by a decrease in ERK1/2 phosphorylation compared with control cells.
In a mouse model of antigen-induced inflammatory arthritis, intraarticular injection of Sdc3-/- MSCs yielded enhanced recovery compared to injection of wild type MSCs.
In conclusion, our data suggest that syndecan-3 regulates MSC adhesion and efficacy in inflammatory arthritis, likely via induction of the AKT pathway (Figure 1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:block;&#34; id=&#34;fig:figure1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;Loss of SCD3 in MSCs causes increased ATK phosphorylation and a reduction in ERK phosphorylation.  (A) representative images of blots used for quantification. SDC3 knockout was confirmed for Sdc3-/- MSCs in each sample (B) Total phosphorylated tyrosine normalised to GAPDH. (C) Phosphorylated AKTSer473 was normalised to total AKT. (D) Phosphorylated ERKThr202/Tyr204 was normalised to total ERK. Quantification was performed using ImageJ.&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: Loss of SCD3 in MSCs causes increased ATK phosphorylation and a reduction in ERK phosphorylation. (A) representative images of blots used for quantification. SDC3 knockout was confirmed for Sdc3-/- MSCs in each sample (B) Total phosphorylated tyrosine normalised to GAPDH. (C) Phosphorylated AKTSer473 was normalised to total AKT. (D) Phosphorylated ERKThr202/Tyr204 was normalised to total ERK. Quantification was performed using ImageJ.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can cells from umbilical cords be used to treat patients with osteoarthritis?</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/can-cells-from-umbilical-cords-be-used-to-treat-patients-with-osteoarthritis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/can-cells-from-umbilical-cords-be-used-to-treat-patients-with-osteoarthritis/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Osteoarthritis (OA) is a complex degenerative joint disease, characterised by degradation and loss of articular cartilage (causing the joint space to narrow), as well as a lot of changes in the bone, such as abnormal bony spurs or ‘osteophytes’ forming.
Currently, there are no effective pharmaceutical or non-surgical therapies to reverse osteoarthritis. Researchers around the world are seeking new approaches, including seeing if a biological approach such as cell therapy could be useful.
Here in Oswestry, we have been obtaining mesenchymal stromal or stem cells (MSCs) from human umbilical cords (UC-MSCs) for some years now. These are an attractive source of cells for regenerative medicine since they are fairly easy to obtain and grow and they also appear to have anti-inflammatory properties, which may be useful and make an immune reaction less likely if used in a different individual.&lt;br /&gt;
We are currently working with collaborators in other universities to see if the cells prepared here in Oswestry could delay osteoarthritis in their models.
Specifically, we are examining the effect of a single injection of UC-MSCs to determine if they can help repair or regenerate damaged joints.
If successful, it is likely they could be an excellent allogeneic (i.e. from another person) source of cells for the treatment of OA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of these (called the PMM or partial medial meniscectomy model) mimics end-stage osteoarthritis, with severe loss of cartilage and osteophyte formation appearing in the operated groups.
Our results demonstrated that although the transplanted UC-MSCs did not recover joint damage induced by the PMM, as assessed histologically or by micro computed tomography (micro CT), the implanted cells did not appear to elicit an inflammatory response in the treated groups, even though they were from a different species (at least at the timepoints examined).
Furthermore, there was marked variability between the UC donors, with a significantly reduced loss of joint space appearing at 12 weeks with one donor but not the other 2 donors’ cells. This suggests that some donors’ cells may have a greater therapeutic potential than others, highlighting the importance of characterising each batch of cells for allogeneic cell therapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second model used a small isolated injury to the cartilage, which can lead to secondary osteoarthritis (and so significantly less severe than the aforementioned model).
In this injury model we compared human UC-MSCs and bone marrow (BM)-derived MSCs, grown in a bioreactor (Quantum®), at repairing cartilage damage and preventing secondary OA.
As in the other study, the groups treated with cells did not appear to show any macroscopic or microscopic signs of swelling/inflammation due to human cell implantation.
Furthermore, when assessed histologically both human MSC treated groups had significantly better repair compared with the untreated group (ie without cells; Figure 7).
Additionally, immunohistochemistry showed that there was more type II collagen in the repair tissue of those joints with better cartilage morphologically, as well as it containing many ‘tomato’-positive cells (which are derived from the joint interzone).
These results suggest that up-scale manufactured UC-MSCs and BM-MSCs could be an effective therapy for treating cartilage injuries.
The implanted MSCs did not appear to elicit an inflammatory response, further supporting their potential as an allogeneic treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcriptome analysis of the umbilical cord-MSCs&#39; therapeutic response to inflammation</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/transcriptome-analysis-of-the-umbilical-cord-mesenchymal-stromal-cells-therapeutic-response-to-inflammation-with-a-view-to-banking-the-most-potent-cells-for-allogeneic-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/transcriptome-analysis-of-the-umbilical-cord-mesenchymal-stromal-cells-therapeutic-response-to-inflammation-with-a-view-to-banking-the-most-potent-cells-for-allogeneic-therapy/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Mesenchymal Stromal Cells (MSCs) isolated from bone marrow (BM) are considered to be the “gold standard” for MSC populations which can be used for cell therapy.
However, sourcing them can be painful and provide limited numbers of cells. Umbilical Cords (UCs) show great potential as an alternative source of MSCs as they are normally thrown away and also UC-MSCs proliferate faster in culture than BM-MSCs, allowing larger numbers to be produced quicker which would be necessary for creating large numbers of allogeneic cells for treating greater numbers of patients.
UC-derived MSCs also have an immune-privileged status and an immunomodulatory phenotype (meaning they are less likely to elicit an immune response when used in a person they were not sourced from), again making them attractive candidates for allogeneic cell based therapies.
Previous work in our group has focussed on sourcing MSCs from whole UC and characterising the cells’ modulatory properties in an inflammatory environment, such as that which may be found in an inflamed joint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The International Society for Cell Therapy (ISCT) advises that characterisation of MSCs destined for cell therapy should include activation or ‘licensing’, which involves stimulation with inflammatory molecules such as interferon gamma (IFN-γ), either alone or with TNF-&lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(\alpha\)&lt;/span&gt;.
These molecules are often found in joints of patients with rheumatoid arthritis or osteoarthritis.&lt;br /&gt;
The production of molecule such as indoleamine 2,3-dioxygenase (IDO), which are known to dampen down inflammation, only occurs following activation with these inflammatory cytokines. We have found, however, that different peoples’ cells can respond differently in how much IDO they produce.&lt;br /&gt;
This suggests that it would be important for cells destined for allogeneic cell banks to have their immunomodulatory potential tested prior to banking, to characterise the response to inflammatory cytokines for each donor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are working on using state of the art RNA-sequencing of the transcriptome of UC-MSC donors with either high or low response to inflammatory cytokines (as assessed via IDO gene expression). This should help to identify the most potent cells for allogeneic cell therapy and cell banking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cell therapy for repair of cartilage defects in the ankle - how does it work and who should we treat?</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/cell-therapy-for-repair-of-cartilage-defects-in-the-ankle-how-does-it-work-and-who-should-we-treat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/cell-therapy-for-repair-of-cartilage-defects-in-the-ankle-how-does-it-work-and-who-should-we-treat/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Untreated cartilage defects in the ankle can lead to osteoarthritis (OA).
Various versions of a cell therapy, using a one-step arthroscopic technique to deliver bone-marrow aspirate concentrate (BMAC) into a cartilage defect to delay the development of OA have been used in the ankle at RJAH.
Previously used to treat cartilage defects in the knee1, one such technique called Complete Cartilage Repair (CCR) has been used at RJAH for the treatment of cartilage defects in the ankle (n=62)2.
Preliminary data from our laboratory using such patients BMAC samples have demonstrated that not all cells adhere to a traditional mesenchymal stem cell (MSC) phenotype, thus questioning the suggested mechanism of action.
This reverse-translational study aims to establish the exact cell population/s obtained via BMAC (in both commercially available normal and patient samples); we aim to assess their chondrogenic potency and phenotype and how these cells might relate to a good clinical outcome.
Furthermore, we will aim to identify biomarkers within the synovial fluid and bloods which may predict which patients are most likely to benefit from this treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commercially-available bone marrow aspirate from young, healthy donors will be concentrated via centrifugation using the three BMAC preparation kits trialled clinically in our centre (Complete Cartilage Repair (CCR), RegenGlobal; Heragen® Maxx, Heraeus; and Angel® BMC, Arthrex).
Flow cytometry and qRT-PCR will be used to characterise the cell phenotype/s and assess their chondrogenic potency.
Additionally, how BMAC cells respond to the environment within the scaffold used in the CCR kit is unknown.
Therefore, cells will be seeded within this scaffold in the laboratory and their viability and chondrogenic potency assessed by live/dead assays and qRT-PCR, respectively.
Synovial fluid and bloods will be collected from patients at the time of BMAC (CCR) implantation and a panel of protein markers, found to predict clinical outcome following knee surgery3-5, will be assessed to identify proteins that may predict clinical outcome following treatment.
At 6 and 12 months post-treatment, clinical outcome and general well-being of the patients enrolled in this study will be assessed using a validated foot and ankle questionnaire (MOXFQ) and the EQ5D questionnaire, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The comparison of the three different preparation kits will indicate which preparation yields the most suitable cell type/s for cartilage repair.
This will provide clinically relevant information which could contribute to a clinical trial application and for seeking more substantive scientific funding.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Up-scaling UC-MSC extracellular vesicle production for rheumatoid arthritis treatment</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/up-scaling-uc-msc-extracellular-vesicle-production-for-rheumatoid-arthritis-treatment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/up-scaling-uc-msc-extracellular-vesicle-production-for-rheumatoid-arthritis-treatment/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;The anti-inflammatory properties of umbilical cord mesenchymal stromal cells (UC-MSCs) make them an attractive source for cells therapies of inflammatory based disorders, including rheumatoid arthritis (RA). Yet, extracellular vesicles, which are small membrane bound particles, can recapitulate these advantageous properties through the delivery of biological cargo (protein and RNA) thereby removing concerns with safety and practicality associated with cell therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project aims to tackle some of the challenges of EV research by up-scaling UC-MSC vesicle production and exploring their subsequent characteristics and immunomodulatory potential, with particular attention given to their ability to treat RA. To do this, we will:
Determine the optimal conditions to harvest and enrich UC-MSC EVs, in which a comparison of EV collection media was performed to investigate resulting cellular attributes and EV production before conducting a trial of three EV enrichment protocols (ultracentrifugation, sucrose cushion and size exclusion chromatography).
Characterise single donor UC-MSC EVs to compare to an allogeneic strategy of EV production, to explore whether combining donors changes the resulting EV profile, with particular attention paid to their protein cargo and immunomodulatory properties.
Compare the ability of UC-MSC EVs to treat an inflammatory model of arthritis with their parental cells, by assessing their resulting histology and T-cell subsets.
Achieve the large-scale production of UC-MSC EVs using the Quantum cell expansion system, to see how this changes EV characteristics assessed previously, and how effective these EVs are at promoting an anti-inflammatory phenotype in RA derived PBMCs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human adipose tissue-derived mesenchymal stem/stromal cells adhere to and inhibit the growth of Staphylococcus aureus and Pseudomonas aeruginosa</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/human-adipose-tissue-derived-mesenchymal-stem-stromal-cells-adhere-to-and-inhibit-the-growth-of-staphylococcus-aureus-and-pseudomonas-aeruginosa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/human-adipose-tissue-derived-mesenchymal-stem-stromal-cells-adhere-to-and-inhibit-the-growth-of-staphylococcus-aureus-and-pseudomonas-aeruginosa/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/human-adipose-tissue-derived-mesenchymal-stem-stromal-cells-adhere-to-and-inhibit-the-growth-of-staphylococcus-aureus-and-pseudomonas-aeruginosa/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficacy and safety of autologous cell therapies for knee cartilage defects (autologous stem cells, chondrocytes or the two): randomized controlled trial design</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/efficacy-and-safety-of-autologous-cell-therapies-for-knee-cartilage-defects-autologous-stem-cells-chondrocytes-or-the-two-randomized-controlled-trial-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/efficacy-and-safety-of-autologous-cell-therapies-for-knee-cartilage-defects-autologous-stem-cells-chondrocytes-or-the-two-randomized-controlled-trial-design/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/efficacy-and-safety-of-autologous-cell-therapies-for-knee-cartilage-defects-autologous-stem-cells-chondrocytes-or-the-two-randomized-controlled-trial-design/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesenchymal Stem Cell Therapy in Rheumatoid Arthritis</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/mesenchymal-stem-cell-therapy-in-rheumatoid-arthritis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/mesenchymal-stem-cell-therapy-in-rheumatoid-arthritis/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/mesenchymal-stem-cell-therapy-in-rheumatoid-arthritis/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chondrogenic Potency Analyses of Donor-Matched Chondrocytes and Mesenchymal Stem Cells Derived from Bone Marrow, Infrapatellar Fat Pad, and Subcutaneous Fat</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/chondrogenic-potency-analyses-of-donor-matched-chondrocytes-and-mesenchymal-stem-cells-derived-from-bone-marrow-infrapatellar-fat-pad-and-subcutaneous-fat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/chondrogenic-potency-analyses-of-donor-matched-chondrocytes-and-mesenchymal-stem-cells-derived-from-bone-marrow-infrapatellar-fat-pad-and-subcutaneous-fat/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/chondrogenic-potency-analyses-of-donor-matched-chondrocytes-and-mesenchymal-stem-cells-derived-from-bone-marrow-infrapatellar-fat-pad-and-subcutaneous-fat/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human mesenchymal stem cells stimulate EaHy926 endothelial cell migration: combined proteomic and in vitro analysis of the influence of donor-donor variability</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/human-mesenchymal-stem-cells-stimulate-eahy926-endothelial-cell-migration-combined-proteomic-and-in-vitro-analysis-of-the-influence-of-donor-donor-variability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/human-mesenchymal-stem-cells-stimulate-eahy926-endothelial-cell-migration-combined-proteomic-and-in-vitro-analysis-of-the-influence-of-donor-donor-variability/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/human-mesenchymal-stem-cells-stimulate-eahy926-endothelial-cell-migration-combined-proteomic-and-in-vitro-analysis-of-the-influence-of-donor-donor-variability/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High content and high throughput screening to assess the angiogenic and neurogenic actions of mesenchymal stem cells in vitro</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/high-content-and-high-throughput-screening-to-assess-the-angiogenic-and-neurogenic-actions-of-mesenchymal-stem-cells-in-vitro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/high-content-and-high-throughput-screening-to-assess-the-angiogenic-and-neurogenic-actions-of-mesenchymal-stem-cells-in-vitro/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/high-content-and-high-throughput-screening-to-assess-the-angiogenic-and-neurogenic-actions-of-mesenchymal-stem-cells-in-vitro/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intra-articular injection of mesenchymal stem cells leads to reduced inflammation and cartilage damage in murine antigen-induced arthritis</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/intra-articular-injection-of-mesenchymal-stem-cells-leads-to-reduced-inflammation-and-cartilage-damage-in-murine-antigen-induced-arthritis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/intra-articular-injection-of-mesenchymal-stem-cells-leads-to-reduced-inflammation-and-cartilage-damage-in-murine-antigen-induced-arthritis/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/intra-articular-injection-of-mesenchymal-stem-cells-leads-to-reduced-inflammation-and-cartilage-damage-in-murine-antigen-induced-arthritis/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mesenchymal stem cell-conditioned medium accelerates skin wound healing: An in vitro study of fibroblast and keratinocyte scratch assays</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/mesenchymal-stem-cell-conditioned-medium-accelerates-skin-wound-healing-an-in-vitro-study-of-fibroblast-and-keratinocyte-scratch-assays/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/mesenchymal-stem-cell-conditioned-medium-accelerates-skin-wound-healing-an-in-vitro-study-of-fibroblast-and-keratinocyte-scratch-assays/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/mesenchymal-stem-cell-conditioned-medium-accelerates-skin-wound-healing-an-in-vitro-study-of-fibroblast-and-keratinocyte-scratch-assays/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Murine Mesenchymal Stem Cells Exhibit a Restricted Repertoire of Functional Chemokine Receptors: Comparison with Human</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/murine-mesenchymal-stem-cells-exhibit-a-restricted-repertoire-of-functional-chemokine-receptors-comparison-with-human/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/murine-mesenchymal-stem-cells-exhibit-a-restricted-repertoire-of-functional-chemokine-receptors-comparison-with-human/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/murine-mesenchymal-stem-cells-exhibit-a-restricted-repertoire-of-functional-chemokine-receptors-comparison-with-human/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
