<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Knee | Oswestry Keele Orthopaedic Research group - OsKOR</title>
    <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/tag/knee/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://oskor.netlify.app/tag/knee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Knee</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://oskor.netlify.app/media/logo_hu0e35ae0aaba2517cccb2b0d7ca3e2f28_296151_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url>
      <title>Knee</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/tag/knee/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Severity of Synovitis and Macrophage Phenotypes in Knee Cartilage Defect and Osteoarthritis Cohorts</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/severity-of-synovitis-and-macrophage-phenotypes-in-knee-cartilage-defect-and-osteoarthritis-cohorts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/severity-of-synovitis-and-macrophage-phenotypes-in-knee-cartilage-defect-and-osteoarthritis-cohorts/</guid>
      <description>


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tissue engineering of meniscus cells, bmscs, chondrocytes and co-cultures on a scaffolds</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/cell-based-meniscus-tissue-engineering-comparing-meniscus-cells-chondrocytes-bmscs-and-co-cultures-on-synthetic-scaffolds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/cell-based-meniscus-tissue-engineering-comparing-meniscus-cells-chondrocytes-bmscs-and-co-cultures-on-synthetic-scaffolds/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Menisci play an important role in force transmission, shock absorption, joint stability, lubrication, and proprioception of the knee joint.
Meniscus tears are the most commonly observed intra-articular knee injury. In the UK, there are 60-70 meniscal injuries each year per 100,000 people.
When the irreparable meniscus (the inner avascular zone with no blood vessels in) is damaged, the articular cartilage of the knee joint is exposed to excessive loading, which eventually increases the risk of early osteoarthritis.
Currently, two scaffolds are used in clinic in a cell-free approach as replacement menisci: CMI® (collagen scaffold) and Actifit® (polyurethane scaffold).
Though both scaffolds sometimes show some clinical benefit, there remain limitations: the grafts shrink, do not integrate well with the patients’ own tissues and they have a fairly high failure rate.
Therefore, we aim to see if adding cells to these scaffolds would improve things. Meniscal cells, cartilage cells (chondrocytes) and mesenchymal stromal/stem cells (MSCs) from bone marrow are being studied in this project as potential cell sources.&lt;br /&gt;
This work is forming a PhD for a Chinese orthopaedic surgeon (Jingsong Wang) who is in his second year.
He aims to develop ways of seeding cells into the synthetic scaffolds and see how effective they will be at synthesising the molecules needed for a healthy meniscus.
Currently he is testing different formulations of fibrin glue for this purpose.
The results of this study will hopefully determine whether this approach can be applied in the clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jingsong, with other members of the team have also just published a case report looking at 2 patients (A and B) who have previously been treated by Prof Richardson with a combination of cells (both autologous chondrocytes and MSCs from the patients’ bone marrow), 8 and 9 years ago.
Interestingly both patients appear to have improved for longer than might be expected, with defects or lesions seen on MRI in their bone beneath the cartilage appearing less obvious with time (Figure 8).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biological, physical and psychosocial factors that affect the health of the human knee</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/biological-physical-and-psychosocial-factors-that-affect-the-health-of-the-human-knee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/biological-physical-and-psychosocial-factors-that-affect-the-health-of-the-human-knee/</guid>
      <description>


This project uses several different approaches to investigate factors that have an impact on human knee health. Osteoarthritis (OA) is the most common joint disease in the world, but its onset and progression are still not fully understood.
Although traditionally considered specifically a disease of the articular cartilage (AC), OA is now regarded as an ‘organ-level failure’ that affects and involves all tissues of the joint rather than the AC alone.
Of these tissues, the subchondral bone (SB) is of particular interest given the close physical interaction and shared signalling pathways between the two tissues.
In this part of the project, a series of experiments are being performed to test if cells taken from healthy areas of the SB, and those taken from unhealthy areas of the SB, have different characteristics that could point to their involvement in OA (figure 2 and 3).
Subsequently, we are investigating whether cells from these different regions have different effects on the characteristics of cells isolated from the cartilage (chondrocytes). This is carried out using a ‘co-culture’ model (figure 4), in which the cells from the SB and cells from the AC are grown together but separated by a membrane that prevents contact but allows communication between the cells.
The aim of this part of the project is to try and characterise the relationship between the AC and SB and the part that this relationship plays on the onset and progression of OA in the knee.&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:block;&#34; id=&#34;fig:unnamed-chunk-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;Schematic illustrating the co-culture system of bone and cartilage cells.&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: Schematic illustrating the co-culture system of bone and cartilage cells.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another part of this project is based in the clinic.
A patient;s knee function is known to vary over their lifetime.
However, there also appears to be variation over a more short-term basis, week-to-week or even day-to-day.
One factor thought to play a part in this variability is the patient’s activity levels.
We have recently shown, in a study of 64 patients undergoing rehabilitation following cell therapy, that the relationship between activity levels and knee function varies significantly between patients (a sample of these patients is shown in Figure 5).
We then sought to find factors that could explain this variation between patients.
Affect, the feeling of emotion, is described in terms of positive and negative and is known to vary between patients and influence perceived disease symptoms.
We demonstrated that patients with a high positive affect score and low negative affect score are more likely to report improved knee function with increased activity levels and vice versa.
This has implications for the prescription of rehabilitation. We now plan to build on this study, which used an activity questionnaire, using wearable activity trackers (Figure 6) to provide a more accurate measure of patients’ activity levels, alongside validated scoring systems for knee function and attitudes to pain.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can cells from umbilical cords be used to treat patients with osteoarthritis?</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/can-cells-from-umbilical-cords-be-used-to-treat-patients-with-osteoarthritis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/can-cells-from-umbilical-cords-be-used-to-treat-patients-with-osteoarthritis/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Osteoarthritis (OA) is a complex degenerative joint disease, characterised by degradation and loss of articular cartilage (causing the joint space to narrow), as well as a lot of changes in the bone, such as abnormal bony spurs or ‘osteophytes’ forming.
Currently, there are no effective pharmaceutical or non-surgical therapies to reverse osteoarthritis. Researchers around the world are seeking new approaches, including seeing if a biological approach such as cell therapy could be useful.
Here in Oswestry, we have been obtaining mesenchymal stromal or stem cells (MSCs) from human umbilical cords (UC-MSCs) for some years now. These are an attractive source of cells for regenerative medicine since they are fairly easy to obtain and grow and they also appear to have anti-inflammatory properties, which may be useful and make an immune reaction less likely if used in a different individual.&lt;br /&gt;
We are currently working with collaborators in other universities to see if the cells prepared here in Oswestry could delay osteoarthritis in their models.
Specifically, we are examining the effect of a single injection of UC-MSCs to determine if they can help repair or regenerate damaged joints.
If successful, it is likely they could be an excellent allogeneic (i.e. from another person) source of cells for the treatment of OA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of these (called the PMM or partial medial meniscectomy model) mimics end-stage osteoarthritis, with severe loss of cartilage and osteophyte formation appearing in the operated groups.
Our results demonstrated that although the transplanted UC-MSCs did not recover joint damage induced by the PMM, as assessed histologically or by micro computed tomography (micro CT), the implanted cells did not appear to elicit an inflammatory response in the treated groups, even though they were from a different species (at least at the timepoints examined).
Furthermore, there was marked variability between the UC donors, with a significantly reduced loss of joint space appearing at 12 weeks with one donor but not the other 2 donors’ cells. This suggests that some donors’ cells may have a greater therapeutic potential than others, highlighting the importance of characterising each batch of cells for allogeneic cell therapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second model used a small isolated injury to the cartilage, which can lead to secondary osteoarthritis (and so significantly less severe than the aforementioned model).
In this injury model we compared human UC-MSCs and bone marrow (BM)-derived MSCs, grown in a bioreactor (Quantum®), at repairing cartilage damage and preventing secondary OA.
As in the other study, the groups treated with cells did not appear to show any macroscopic or microscopic signs of swelling/inflammation due to human cell implantation.
Furthermore, when assessed histologically both human MSC treated groups had significantly better repair compared with the untreated group (ie without cells; Figure 7).
Additionally, immunohistochemistry showed that there was more type II collagen in the repair tissue of those joints with better cartilage morphologically, as well as it containing many ‘tomato’-positive cells (which are derived from the joint interzone).
These results suggest that up-scale manufactured UC-MSCs and BM-MSCs could be an effective therapy for treating cartilage injuries.
The implanted MSCs did not appear to elicit an inflammatory response, further supporting their potential as an allogeneic treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of Candidate Synovial Fluid Biomarkers for the Prediction of Patient Outcome After Microfracture or Osteotomy</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/identification-of-candidate-synovial-fluid-biomarkers-for-the-prediction-of-patient-outcome-after-microfracture-or-osteotomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/identification-of-candidate-synovial-fluid-biomarkers-for-the-prediction-of-patient-outcome-after-microfracture-or-osteotomy/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/identification-of-candidate-synovial-fluid-biomarkers-for-the-prediction-of-patient-outcome-after-microfracture-or-osteotomy/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic Resonance Imaging Parameters at 1 Year Correlate With Clinical Outcomes Up to 17 Years After Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/magnetic-resonance-imaging-parameters-at-1-year-correlate-with-clinical-outcomes-up-to-17-years-after-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/magnetic-resonance-imaging-parameters-at-1-year-correlate-with-clinical-outcomes-up-to-17-years-after-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/magnetic-resonance-imaging-parameters-at-1-year-correlate-with-clinical-outcomes-up-to-17-years-after-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Absence of Detectable ADAMTS-4 (Aggrecanase-1) Activity in Synovial Fluid Is a Predictive Indicator of Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation Success</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/the-absence-of-detectable-adamts-4-aggrecanase-1-activity-in-synovial-fluid-is-a-predictive-indicator-of-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/the-absence-of-detectable-adamts-4-aggrecanase-1-activity-in-synovial-fluid-is-a-predictive-indicator-of-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation-success/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/the-absence-of-detectable-adamts-4-aggrecanase-1-activity-in-synovial-fluid-is-a-predictive-indicator-of-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation-success/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autologous Bone Plug Supplemented With Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation in Osteochondral Defects of the Knee</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/autologous-bone-plug-supplemented-with-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation-in-osteochondral-defects-of-the-knee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/autologous-bone-plug-supplemented-with-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation-in-osteochondral-defects-of-the-knee/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/autologous-bone-plug-supplemented-with-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation-in-osteochondral-defects-of-the-knee/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intra-articular injection of mesenchymal stem cells leads to reduced inflammation and cartilage damage in murine antigen-induced arthritis</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/intra-articular-injection-of-mesenchymal-stem-cells-leads-to-reduced-inflammation-and-cartilage-damage-in-murine-antigen-induced-arthritis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/intra-articular-injection-of-mesenchymal-stem-cells-leads-to-reduced-inflammation-and-cartilage-damage-in-murine-antigen-induced-arthritis/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/intra-articular-injection-of-mesenchymal-stem-cells-leads-to-reduced-inflammation-and-cartilage-damage-in-murine-antigen-induced-arthritis/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
