<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Completed projects | Oswestry Keele Orthopaedic Research group - OsKOR</title>
    <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/tag/completed-projects/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://oskor.netlify.app/tag/completed-projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Completed projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://oskor.netlify.app/media/logo_hu0e35ae0aaba2517cccb2b0d7ca3e2f28_296151_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url>
      <title>Completed projects</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/tag/completed-projects/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSCs-Derived Extracellular Vesicles Attenuate Disease Severity in Inflammatory Arthritis</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/mscs-evs-inlfamm-arthritis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/mscs-evs-inlfamm-arthritis/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Rheumatoid arthritis is a painful autoimmune disorder characterised by synovial inflammation that leads to progressive destruction of articular cartilage.
There is no cure for RA and life expectancy of sufferers may be reduced by up to 18 years. For that reason, it is vital to develop a new and more effective therapy for RA.
Mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) possess anti-inflammatory and immunosuppressive properties and function predominantly through paracrine mechanisms, via growth factors, cytokines, chemokines and bioactive, membrane-bound extracellular vesicles (EVs) found in mesenchymal stem cell conditioned medium (CM-MSC).
Our previous project demonstrated that CM-MSC reduces swelling and cartilage destruction through modulation of the immune response in a murine model of inflammatory arthritis.
This current study is assessing the contribution of extracellular vesicles to this therapeutic outcome, and examining how the culture microenvironment of MSCs can be manipulated to enhance their therapeutic effectiveness.
Extracellular vesicles are applied as a treatment in our pre-clinical model of experimental arthritis, looking at their effects on inflammation, histological outcomes of disease progression and T cell polarisation towards either pro- or anti-inflammatory cell types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stem cells isolated from human bone marrow aspirate were used to derive extracellular vesicles. Following the application of vesicles, knee joint swelling significantly reduced at both 24 and 48 hours after treatment in our pre-clinical model (Figure 1). Reductions were highly significant in comparison to control animals where knee joints continued to swell in the absence of extracellular vesicles.
Histological analysis reviled improved scores for cartilage and arthritis index (Figure 2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The significant reduction in joint swelling following EVs treatment demonstrates their effectiveness as a new therapeutic intervention.
Further investigation will identify the mechanisms involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:block;&#34; id=&#34;fig:figures&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;figure1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Therapeutic outcomes in an inflammatory arthritis model (AIA). Alleviation of joint swelling as a measure of therapeutic efficacy following EV treatments show significant influence of EVs compared to controls at day 2 and day 3 after arthritis induction, normalised to peak swelling.&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: Therapeutic outcomes in an inflammatory arthritis model (AIA). Alleviation of joint swelling as a measure of therapeutic efficacy following EV treatments show significant influence of EVs compared to controls at day 2 and day 3 after arthritis induction, normalised to peak swelling.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:block;&#34; id=&#34;fig:fig2&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;Examination of histological signs of arthritis pathogenesis following EV treatment shows significant therapeutic effects of EVs sourced from normoxic and pro-inflammatory pre-conditioned MSC cultures.&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 2: Examination of histological signs of arthritis pathogenesis following EV treatment shows significant therapeutic effects of EVs sourced from normoxic and pro-inflammatory pre-conditioned MSC cultures.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syndecan-3 plays a role in MSC adhesion and efficacy in an in vivo model of inflammatory arthritis</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/syndecan-3-regulates-msc-adhesion-erk-and-akt-signaling-in-vitro-and-its-deletion-enhances-msc-efficacy-in-a-model-of-inflammatory-arthritis-in-vivo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/syndecan-3-regulates-msc-adhesion-erk-and-akt-signaling-in-vitro-and-its-deletion-enhances-msc-efficacy-in-a-model-of-inflammatory-arthritis-in-vivo/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Inflammation is a central feature of rheumatoid arthritis that affects around 1% of the population and can result in disability and morbidity.
The immunomodulatory effects of bone marrow derived mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) has been widely studied and the recent observations that syndecan-3 (SDC3) is selectively pro-inflammatory in the joint led us to hypothesise that SDC3 might play an important role in MSC biology.
MSCs isolated from bone marrow of wild type and Sdc3-/- mice were used to assess immunophenotype, differentiation, adhesion and migration properties and cell signalling pathways.
While both cell types show similar differentiation potential and forward scatter values, the cell complexity in wild type MSCs was significantly higher than in Sdc3-/- cells and was accompanied by lower spread surface area.
Moreover, Sdc3-/- MSCs adhered more rapidly to collagen type I and showed a dramatic increase in AKT phosphorylation, accompanied by a decrease in ERK1/2 phosphorylation compared with control cells.
In a mouse model of antigen-induced inflammatory arthritis, intraarticular injection of Sdc3-/- MSCs yielded enhanced recovery compared to injection of wild type MSCs.
In conclusion, our data suggest that syndecan-3 regulates MSC adhesion and efficacy in inflammatory arthritis, likely via induction of the AKT pathway (Figure 1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:block;&#34; id=&#34;fig:figure1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;Loss of SCD3 in MSCs causes increased ATK phosphorylation and a reduction in ERK phosphorylation.  (A) representative images of blots used for quantification. SDC3 knockout was confirmed for Sdc3-/- MSCs in each sample (B) Total phosphorylated tyrosine normalised to GAPDH. (C) Phosphorylated AKTSer473 was normalised to total AKT. (D) Phosphorylated ERKThr202/Tyr204 was normalised to total ERK. Quantification was performed using ImageJ.&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: Loss of SCD3 in MSCs causes increased ATK phosphorylation and a reduction in ERK phosphorylation. (A) representative images of blots used for quantification. SDC3 knockout was confirmed for Sdc3-/- MSCs in each sample (B) Total phosphorylated tyrosine normalised to GAPDH. (C) Phosphorylated AKTSer473 was normalised to total AKT. (D) Phosphorylated ERKThr202/Tyr204 was normalised to total ERK. Quantification was performed using ImageJ.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tissue engineering of meniscus cells, bmscs, chondrocytes and co-cultures on a scaffolds</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/cell-based-meniscus-tissue-engineering-comparing-meniscus-cells-chondrocytes-bmscs-and-co-cultures-on-synthetic-scaffolds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/cell-based-meniscus-tissue-engineering-comparing-meniscus-cells-chondrocytes-bmscs-and-co-cultures-on-synthetic-scaffolds/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Menisci play an important role in force transmission, shock absorption, joint stability, lubrication, and proprioception of the knee joint.
Meniscus tears are the most commonly observed intra-articular knee injury. In the UK, there are 60-70 meniscal injuries each year per 100,000 people.
When the irreparable meniscus (the inner avascular zone with no blood vessels in) is damaged, the articular cartilage of the knee joint is exposed to excessive loading, which eventually increases the risk of early osteoarthritis.
Currently, two scaffolds are used in clinic in a cell-free approach as replacement menisci: CMI® (collagen scaffold) and Actifit® (polyurethane scaffold).
Though both scaffolds sometimes show some clinical benefit, there remain limitations: the grafts shrink, do not integrate well with the patients’ own tissues and they have a fairly high failure rate.
Therefore, we aim to see if adding cells to these scaffolds would improve things. Meniscal cells, cartilage cells (chondrocytes) and mesenchymal stromal/stem cells (MSCs) from bone marrow are being studied in this project as potential cell sources.&lt;br /&gt;
This work is forming a PhD for a Chinese orthopaedic surgeon (Jingsong Wang) who is in his second year.
He aims to develop ways of seeding cells into the synthetic scaffolds and see how effective they will be at synthesising the molecules needed for a healthy meniscus.
Currently he is testing different formulations of fibrin glue for this purpose.
The results of this study will hopefully determine whether this approach can be applied in the clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jingsong, with other members of the team have also just published a case report looking at 2 patients (A and B) who have previously been treated by Prof Richardson with a combination of cells (both autologous chondrocytes and MSCs from the patients’ bone marrow), 8 and 9 years ago.
Interestingly both patients appear to have improved for longer than might be expected, with defects or lesions seen on MRI in their bone beneath the cartilage appearing less obvious with time (Figure 8).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
