<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation | Oswestry Keele Orthopaedic Research group - OsKOR</title>
    <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/tag/autologous-chondrocyte-implantation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://oskor.netlify.app/tag/autologous-chondrocyte-implantation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://oskor.netlify.app/media/logo_hu0e35ae0aaba2517cccb2b0d7ca3e2f28_296151_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url>
      <title>Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/tag/autologous-chondrocyte-implantation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biomarker discovery in orthopaedics: Matching patients to the best treatment</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/biomarker-discovery-in-orthopaedics-matching-patients-to-the-best-treatment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/biomarker-discovery-in-orthopaedics-matching-patients-to-the-best-treatment/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;As in all treatments, a few patients who have their osteoarthritis treated using biological approaches, such as cell therapies, osteotomy or microfracture, do not respond so well as others, though we do not know why.
Our previous work has identified particular molecules in synovial fluid or blood known as ‘biomarkers’ that have the potential to identify which patients are unlikely to improve clinically following the cell therapy known as autologous chondrocyte implantation (ACI).
These investigations focussed on protein markers whose biology is known to relate to poor repair of cartilage or general inflammation e.g. an enzyme, aggrecanase-1, and another molecule involved in the immune system, CD14.
Our recent work, however, has used a highly specialised technique called proteomics to identify larger numbers of proteins which are altered within the synovial fluid in the knee of patients who either do or do not respond well to ACI.
The proteins identified using this approach include many that have never been investigated before and which therefore provide attractive new candidates.
To date, we have confirmed that four of these proteins, S100A13, MMP1, Complement C1S and MMP3, have the potential to inform us of whether or not a patient is suitable to continue through the ACI procedure.
In addition, the MMP candidates have recently been validated in an independent group of patients using a different multi-plex discovery platform, providing added confidence to our results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we have used ‘bioinformatic’ analysis, using complex computer programmes, to inform us of how the ACI procedure may be affecting different biological mechanisms, such as ‘acute phase response signalling’ in individuals who improve following ACI compared to those who do not (Figure 1).
These studies may help us identify ways to improve ACI outcomes for patients in which it would not currently be successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have gone on to see if any of these ‘biomarkers’ can help us predict what the outcome might be following other treatments, such as osteotomy or microfracture.
We have shown that the amount of both S100A13 and the total amount of protein within the synovial fluid before an operation relates to the clinical functional scores that patients achieve a year after their osteotomy.
We hope that this work will help us to identify a reliable panel of molecular markers which can be used to help the surgeon and patient decide on what is the best treatment for that particular person.
This would not only save the health service money, but most importantly get people pain free and back to their normal lives quicker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:block;&#34; id=&#34;fig:proj-fig&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;**Acute Phase Signalling is an example of a biological pathway that is altered in people who do poorly following ACI.** Proteins in red were increased and proteins in green were decreased following initial ACI surgery compared to pre-operative levels. This signalling pathway is therefore likely to be a good target for new drugs to improve the outcome for individuals who currently do not benefit from ACI.&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: &lt;strong&gt;Acute Phase Signalling is an example of a biological pathway that is altered in people who do poorly following ACI.&lt;/strong&gt; Proteins in red were increased and proteins in green were decreased following initial ACI surgery compared to pre-operative levels. This signalling pathway is therefore likely to be a good target for new drugs to improve the outcome for individuals who currently do not benefit from ACI.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of clinical outcome following ACI by magnetic resonance imaging</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/aci_mri_prediction_2021-04-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/aci_mri_prediction_2021-04-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since 2010, we have been collating data from a Retrospective study of Autologous Cell Therapy (REACT), using a postal questionnaire completed by patients who have previously received this treatment here at this hospital for cartilage defects of their knee.
We have assessed the quality of the repair tissue which forms in the treated defect using magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) to see if it correlates with clinical outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found that certain features identifiable on the MRIs correlated significantly with how well the patient felt at a year after treatment (eg the amount and composition of repair tissue which had formed, how well it was integrated with the adjacent cartilage and bone, how smooth the surface was and if there were no cysts in the bone beneath).
What may be particularly useful is that 3 of these parameters at 1 year after treatment (how much tissue, its composition and the smoothness of the surface) all affected the clinical outcome in the long term (up to 17 years after treatment).
This could be particularly useful for clinical trials, meaning that long term follow up such as is ongoing in the Oswestry led multicentre trial of Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation (ACI) in ACTIVE, could be avoided.
Instead of following patients up for 10 years in person, an MRI at 1 year could predict how well those patients would do with this treatment, which could be a huge cost-saving in running such trials. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6081761/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;McCarthy et al (2018) Orthop J Sports Med. 2018 Aug; 6(8): 325967118788280&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combined Autologous Chondrocyte and Bone Marrow Mesenchymal Stromal Cell Implantation in the Knee: An 8-year Follow Up of Two First-In-Man Cases</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/aci_case_study_2021-02-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 15:53:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/aci_case_study_2021-02-01/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regenerative Medicine: A Review of the Evolution of Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation (ACI) Therapy</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/review_evolution_aci_2021-01-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/review_evolution_aci_2021-01-27/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation in Osteochondral Defects of the Talus: Two to Fourteen Year Follow-up Study</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/autologous-chondrocyte-implantation-in-osteochondral-defects-of-the-talus-two-to-fourteen-year-follow-up-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/autologous-chondrocyte-implantation-in-osteochondral-defects-of-the-talus-two-to-fourteen-year-follow-up-study/</guid>
      <description>


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of ACI-Position in the context of other methods/unmet needs in larger defects</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/the-importance-of-aci-position-in-the-context-of-other-methods-unmet-needs-in-larger-defects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/the-importance-of-aci-position-in-the-context-of-other-methods-unmet-needs-in-larger-defects/</guid>
      <description>


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The suitability of pre-operative MRI in predicting accurate cartilage defect sizes in cell therapy</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/the-suitability-of-pre-operative-magnetic-resonance-imaging-in-predicting-accurate-cartilage-defect-sizes-for-treatment-with-cell-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/the-suitability-of-pre-operative-magnetic-resonance-imaging-in-predicting-accurate-cartilage-defect-sizes-for-treatment-with-cell-therapy/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Clinicians are given guidance as to appropriate sizes of cartilage defects to treat with cell therapy.
However, estimating the size of a defect using scans such as magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) may in fact differ from the ‘real-life’ situation.
We performed a retrospective study to evaluate the accuracy of MRI scans to predict the size of articular cartilage lesions in the knee and compared them against actual defect sizes recorded surgically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We included 64 patients, all of whom underwent autologous cell implantation (ACI) performed by two different RJAH surgeons (PDG and JBR).
Each patient received a pre-operative MRI approximately 6 weeks prior to cell implantation.
MRIs were analysed by a Consultant radiologist (BT) and a research PhD student (JP) trained by the radiologist to ascertain the full-thickness defect measurement and the total abnormal defect area that they believed would require debridement (removal of damaged/ unhealthy tissue).
At the time of cell implantation, the Consultant orthopaedic surgeon measured the defect sizes pre- and post-debridement.
The post-debridement surgical measurements have been used as the ‘gold standard’ in this study.
All measurements were further assessed according to defect location within the knee (patella, trochlea, medial or lateral femoral condyle (MFC and LFC)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We assessed a total of 92 cartilage defects and, as expected, found them to be significantly smaller pre-debridement than post-debridement when measured during arthroscopy.
To date, from a radiological perspective (BT), MRI scans significantly underestimated the (pre-debridement) defect size but not the total abnormal area (so this was found to be similar and not significantly different to the post-debridement size measured surgically).&lt;br /&gt;
When considering defect location, MRI still significantly underestimated pre-debridement defect sizes on the patella and MFC but not the LFC and trochlea.
Total abnormal area assessment on MRI was not affected by defect location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This preliminary data indicates that measuring only the full-thickness component of a cartilage defect on MRI will significantly underestimate the area to treat for ACI; evaluating the whole abnormal area will provide a more accurate estimate of the actual defect size requiring treatment. This is critical for surgical planning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two independent proteomic approaches provide a comprehensive analysis of the synovial fluid proteome response to Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/two-independent-proteomic-approaches-provide-a-comprehensive-analysis-of-the-synovial-fluid-proteome-response-to-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/two-independent-proteomic-approaches-provide-a-comprehensive-analysis-of-the-synovial-fluid-proteome-response-to-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/two-independent-proteomic-approaches-provide-a-comprehensive-analysis-of-the-synovial-fluid-proteome-response-to-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autologous chondrocyte implantation-derived synovial fluids display distinct responder and non-responder proteomic profiles</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/autologous-chondrocyte-implantation-derived-synovial-fluids-display-distinct-responder-and-non-responder-proteomic-profiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/autologous-chondrocyte-implantation-derived-synovial-fluids-display-distinct-responder-and-non-responder-proteomic-profiles/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/autologous-chondrocyte-implantation-derived-synovial-fluids-display-distinct-responder-and-non-responder-proteomic-profiles/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Absence of Detectable ADAMTS-4 (Aggrecanase-1) Activity in Synovial Fluid Is a Predictive Indicator of Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation Success</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/the-absence-of-detectable-adamts-4-aggrecanase-1-activity-in-synovial-fluid-is-a-predictive-indicator-of-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/the-absence-of-detectable-adamts-4-aggrecanase-1-activity-in-synovial-fluid-is-a-predictive-indicator-of-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation-success/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/the-absence-of-detectable-adamts-4-aggrecanase-1-activity-in-synovial-fluid-is-a-predictive-indicator-of-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation-success/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autologous Bone Plug Supplemented With Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation in Osteochondral Defects of the Knee</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/autologous-bone-plug-supplemented-with-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation-in-osteochondral-defects-of-the-knee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/autologous-bone-plug-supplemented-with-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation-in-osteochondral-defects-of-the-knee/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/autologous-bone-plug-supplemented-with-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation-in-osteochondral-defects-of-the-knee/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Joint Morbidity after Chondral Harvest for Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation (ACI): A Study of ACI-Treated Ankles and Hips with a Knee Chondral Harvest</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/evaluating-joint-morbidity-after-chondral-harvest-for-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation-aci-a-study-of-aci-treated-ankles-and-hips-with-a-knee-chondral-harvest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/evaluating-joint-morbidity-after-chondral-harvest-for-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation-aci-a-study-of-aci-treated-ankles-and-hips-with-a-knee-chondral-harvest/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/evaluating-joint-morbidity-after-chondral-harvest-for-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation-aci-a-study-of-aci-treated-ankles-and-hips-with-a-knee-chondral-harvest/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A histological comparison of the repair tissue formed when using either Chondrogide(®) or periosteum during autologous chondrocyte implantation</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/a-histological-comparison-of-the-repair-tissue-formed-when-using-either-chondrogide-or-periosteum-during-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/a-histological-comparison-of-the-repair-tissue-formed-when-using-either-chondrogide-or-periosteum-during-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/a-histological-comparison-of-the-repair-tissue-formed-when-using-either-chondrogide-or-periosteum-during-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterization of the cells in repair tissue following autologous chondrocyte implantation in mankind: a novel report of two cases</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/characterization-of-the-cells-in-repair-tissue-following-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation-in-mankind-a-novel-report-of-two-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/characterization-of-the-cells-in-repair-tissue-following-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation-in-mankind-a-novel-report-of-two-cases/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/characterization-of-the-cells-in-repair-tissue-following-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation-in-mankind-a-novel-report-of-two-cases/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
