<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cell therapy | Oswestry Keele Orthopaedic Research group - OsKOR</title>
    <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/tag/cell-therapy/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://oskor.netlify.app/tag/cell-therapy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Cell therapy</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://oskor.netlify.app/media/logo_hu0e35ae0aaba2517cccb2b0d7ca3e2f28_296151_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url>
      <title>Cell therapy</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/tag/cell-therapy/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regenerative Medicine: A Review of the Evolution of Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation (ACI) Therapy</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/review_evolution_aci_2021-01-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/review_evolution_aci_2021-01-27/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cell therapy for cartilage repair</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/cell-therapy-for-cartilage-repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/cell-therapy-for-cartilage-repair/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/cell-therapy-for-cartilage-repair/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The suitability of pre-operative MRI in predicting accurate cartilage defect sizes in cell therapy</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/the-suitability-of-pre-operative-magnetic-resonance-imaging-in-predicting-accurate-cartilage-defect-sizes-for-treatment-with-cell-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/the-suitability-of-pre-operative-magnetic-resonance-imaging-in-predicting-accurate-cartilage-defect-sizes-for-treatment-with-cell-therapy/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Clinicians are given guidance as to appropriate sizes of cartilage defects to treat with cell therapy.
However, estimating the size of a defect using scans such as magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) may in fact differ from the ‘real-life’ situation.
We performed a retrospective study to evaluate the accuracy of MRI scans to predict the size of articular cartilage lesions in the knee and compared them against actual defect sizes recorded surgically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We included 64 patients, all of whom underwent autologous cell implantation (ACI) performed by two different RJAH surgeons (PDG and JBR).
Each patient received a pre-operative MRI approximately 6 weeks prior to cell implantation.
MRIs were analysed by a Consultant radiologist (BT) and a research PhD student (JP) trained by the radiologist to ascertain the full-thickness defect measurement and the total abnormal defect area that they believed would require debridement (removal of damaged/ unhealthy tissue).
At the time of cell implantation, the Consultant orthopaedic surgeon measured the defect sizes pre- and post-debridement.
The post-debridement surgical measurements have been used as the ‘gold standard’ in this study.
All measurements were further assessed according to defect location within the knee (patella, trochlea, medial or lateral femoral condyle (MFC and LFC)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We assessed a total of 92 cartilage defects and, as expected, found them to be significantly smaller pre-debridement than post-debridement when measured during arthroscopy.
To date, from a radiological perspective (BT), MRI scans significantly underestimated the (pre-debridement) defect size but not the total abnormal area (so this was found to be similar and not significantly different to the post-debridement size measured surgically).&lt;br /&gt;
When considering defect location, MRI still significantly underestimated pre-debridement defect sizes on the patella and MFC but not the LFC and trochlea.
Total abnormal area assessment on MRI was not affected by defect location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This preliminary data indicates that measuring only the full-thickness component of a cartilage defect on MRI will significantly underestimate the area to treat for ACI; evaluating the whole abnormal area will provide a more accurate estimate of the actual defect size requiring treatment. This is critical for surgical planning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tissue engineering of meniscus cells, bmscs, chondrocytes and co-cultures on a scaffolds</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/cell-based-meniscus-tissue-engineering-comparing-meniscus-cells-chondrocytes-bmscs-and-co-cultures-on-synthetic-scaffolds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/cell-based-meniscus-tissue-engineering-comparing-meniscus-cells-chondrocytes-bmscs-and-co-cultures-on-synthetic-scaffolds/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Menisci play an important role in force transmission, shock absorption, joint stability, lubrication, and proprioception of the knee joint.
Meniscus tears are the most commonly observed intra-articular knee injury. In the UK, there are 60-70 meniscal injuries each year per 100,000 people.
When the irreparable meniscus (the inner avascular zone with no blood vessels in) is damaged, the articular cartilage of the knee joint is exposed to excessive loading, which eventually increases the risk of early osteoarthritis.
Currently, two scaffolds are used in clinic in a cell-free approach as replacement menisci: CMI® (collagen scaffold) and Actifit® (polyurethane scaffold).
Though both scaffolds sometimes show some clinical benefit, there remain limitations: the grafts shrink, do not integrate well with the patients’ own tissues and they have a fairly high failure rate.
Therefore, we aim to see if adding cells to these scaffolds would improve things. Meniscal cells, cartilage cells (chondrocytes) and mesenchymal stromal/stem cells (MSCs) from bone marrow are being studied in this project as potential cell sources.&lt;br /&gt;
This work is forming a PhD for a Chinese orthopaedic surgeon (Jingsong Wang) who is in his second year.
He aims to develop ways of seeding cells into the synthetic scaffolds and see how effective they will be at synthesising the molecules needed for a healthy meniscus.
Currently he is testing different formulations of fibrin glue for this purpose.
The results of this study will hopefully determine whether this approach can be applied in the clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jingsong, with other members of the team have also just published a case report looking at 2 patients (A and B) who have previously been treated by Prof Richardson with a combination of cells (both autologous chondrocytes and MSCs from the patients’ bone marrow), 8 and 9 years ago.
Interestingly both patients appear to have improved for longer than might be expected, with defects or lesions seen on MRI in their bone beneath the cartilage appearing less obvious with time (Figure 8).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cell therapy for repair of cartilage defects in the ankle - how does it work and who should we treat?</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/cell-therapy-for-repair-of-cartilage-defects-in-the-ankle-how-does-it-work-and-who-should-we-treat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/cell-therapy-for-repair-of-cartilage-defects-in-the-ankle-how-does-it-work-and-who-should-we-treat/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Untreated cartilage defects in the ankle can lead to osteoarthritis (OA).
Various versions of a cell therapy, using a one-step arthroscopic technique to deliver bone-marrow aspirate concentrate (BMAC) into a cartilage defect to delay the development of OA have been used in the ankle at RJAH.
Previously used to treat cartilage defects in the knee1, one such technique called Complete Cartilage Repair (CCR) has been used at RJAH for the treatment of cartilage defects in the ankle (n=62)2.
Preliminary data from our laboratory using such patients BMAC samples have demonstrated that not all cells adhere to a traditional mesenchymal stem cell (MSC) phenotype, thus questioning the suggested mechanism of action.
This reverse-translational study aims to establish the exact cell population/s obtained via BMAC (in both commercially available normal and patient samples); we aim to assess their chondrogenic potency and phenotype and how these cells might relate to a good clinical outcome.
Furthermore, we will aim to identify biomarkers within the synovial fluid and bloods which may predict which patients are most likely to benefit from this treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commercially-available bone marrow aspirate from young, healthy donors will be concentrated via centrifugation using the three BMAC preparation kits trialled clinically in our centre (Complete Cartilage Repair (CCR), RegenGlobal; Heragen® Maxx, Heraeus; and Angel® BMC, Arthrex).
Flow cytometry and qRT-PCR will be used to characterise the cell phenotype/s and assess their chondrogenic potency.
Additionally, how BMAC cells respond to the environment within the scaffold used in the CCR kit is unknown.
Therefore, cells will be seeded within this scaffold in the laboratory and their viability and chondrogenic potency assessed by live/dead assays and qRT-PCR, respectively.
Synovial fluid and bloods will be collected from patients at the time of BMAC (CCR) implantation and a panel of protein markers, found to predict clinical outcome following knee surgery3-5, will be assessed to identify proteins that may predict clinical outcome following treatment.
At 6 and 12 months post-treatment, clinical outcome and general well-being of the patients enrolled in this study will be assessed using a validated foot and ankle questionnaire (MOXFQ) and the EQ5D questionnaire, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The comparison of the three different preparation kits will indicate which preparation yields the most suitable cell type/s for cartilage repair.
This will provide clinically relevant information which could contribute to a clinical trial application and for seeking more substantive scientific funding.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
