<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Arthritis | Oswestry Keele Orthopaedic Research group - OsKOR</title>
    <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/tag/arthritis/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://oskor.netlify.app/tag/arthritis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Arthritis</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://oskor.netlify.app/media/logo_hu0e35ae0aaba2517cccb2b0d7ca3e2f28_296151_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url>
      <title>Arthritis</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/tag/arthritis/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does knee cartilage repair surgery prevent arthritis or the need for a joint replacement?</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/does-knee-cartilage-repair-surgery-prevent-arthritis-or-the-need-for-a-joint-replacement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/does-knee-cartilage-repair-surgery-prevent-arthritis-or-the-need-for-a-joint-replacement/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Musculoskeletal conditions, such as arthritis, account for 20% of GP visits. Arthritis is a wide-spread disease which affects our joints, and osteoarthritis (OA) is the most common form. In the UK, approximately 1/5 of over-45s have been diagnosed with OA, the knee being the most frequently affected joint. The cause of OA is unknown but it develops when cartilage wears out. Knee injury in young adults can increase their risk of developing knee OA sixfold. OA is treated with physiotherapy, painkillers, surgery, or as a last resort, a joint replacement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cartilage repair surgeries focus on stopping knee pain and improving function but may also slow OA. It’s important to measure outcomes following surgery to understand if they have worked. There are different ways to assess outcome for knee cartilage surgery including clinical (e.g., need for re-operation or joint replacement), X-rays, cartilage or bone tests, studying genes or proteins in blood samples, or ‘patient reported’ (e.g., questionnaires). Outcomes are collected and stored in large health databases and registries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally, knee cartilage surgeries in middle-aged patients will slow down OA and delay or eliminate the need for joint replacement. We don’t know if this happens in reality. I plan to work out the true effect of knee cartilage surgeries by studying health records and outcome measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Robert Jones &amp;amp; Agnes Hunt Orthopaedic NHS Hospital in Oswestry specialises in bone and joint disorders. Uniquely, it has cartilage surgery data spanning more than 20 years. I plan to link this information with the National Joint Registry (results from joint replacements) to work out the time from surgery to joint replacement to see if I can predict when and for whom cartilage surgery would be successful. Also, I plan to use the UK Biobank (health records and risk factors for the major diseases of middle and old age) to find out whether cartilage surgery can help patients with a higher genetic risk of OA onset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study will help patients with cartilage defects by giving orthopaedic surgeons a tool to help fit cartilage treatment to their patients to delay or avoid the development of severe OA. This will improve their quality of life and reduce the need for knee replacements, both of which represent health-economic benefits. This potential cost benefit also fits with the NHS national programme “GIRFT” (&lt;a href=&#34;https://gettingitrightfirsttime.co.uk/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://gettingitrightfirsttime.co.uk/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSCs-Derived Extracellular Vesicles Attenuate Disease Severity in Inflammatory Arthritis</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/mscs-evs-inlfamm-arthritis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/mscs-evs-inlfamm-arthritis/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Rheumatoid arthritis is a painful autoimmune disorder characterised by synovial inflammation that leads to progressive destruction of articular cartilage.
There is no cure for RA and life expectancy of sufferers may be reduced by up to 18 years. For that reason, it is vital to develop a new and more effective therapy for RA.
Mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) possess anti-inflammatory and immunosuppressive properties and function predominantly through paracrine mechanisms, via growth factors, cytokines, chemokines and bioactive, membrane-bound extracellular vesicles (EVs) found in mesenchymal stem cell conditioned medium (CM-MSC).
Our previous project demonstrated that CM-MSC reduces swelling and cartilage destruction through modulation of the immune response in a murine model of inflammatory arthritis.
This current study is assessing the contribution of extracellular vesicles to this therapeutic outcome, and examining how the culture microenvironment of MSCs can be manipulated to enhance their therapeutic effectiveness.
Extracellular vesicles are applied as a treatment in our pre-clinical model of experimental arthritis, looking at their effects on inflammation, histological outcomes of disease progression and T cell polarisation towards either pro- or anti-inflammatory cell types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stem cells isolated from human bone marrow aspirate were used to derive extracellular vesicles. Following the application of vesicles, knee joint swelling significantly reduced at both 24 and 48 hours after treatment in our pre-clinical model (Figure 1). Reductions were highly significant in comparison to control animals where knee joints continued to swell in the absence of extracellular vesicles.
Histological analysis reviled improved scores for cartilage and arthritis index (Figure 2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The significant reduction in joint swelling following EVs treatment demonstrates their effectiveness as a new therapeutic intervention.
Further investigation will identify the mechanisms involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:block;&#34; id=&#34;fig:figures&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;figure1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Therapeutic outcomes in an inflammatory arthritis model (AIA). Alleviation of joint swelling as a measure of therapeutic efficacy following EV treatments show significant influence of EVs compared to controls at day 2 and day 3 after arthritis induction, normalised to peak swelling.&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: Therapeutic outcomes in an inflammatory arthritis model (AIA). Alleviation of joint swelling as a measure of therapeutic efficacy following EV treatments show significant influence of EVs compared to controls at day 2 and day 3 after arthritis induction, normalised to peak swelling.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:block;&#34; id=&#34;fig:fig2&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;Examination of histological signs of arthritis pathogenesis following EV treatment shows significant therapeutic effects of EVs sourced from normoxic and pro-inflammatory pre-conditioned MSC cultures.&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 2: Examination of histological signs of arthritis pathogenesis following EV treatment shows significant therapeutic effects of EVs sourced from normoxic and pro-inflammatory pre-conditioned MSC cultures.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syndecan-3 plays a role in MSC adhesion and efficacy in an in vivo model of inflammatory arthritis</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/syndecan-3-regulates-msc-adhesion-erk-and-akt-signaling-in-vitro-and-its-deletion-enhances-msc-efficacy-in-a-model-of-inflammatory-arthritis-in-vivo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/syndecan-3-regulates-msc-adhesion-erk-and-akt-signaling-in-vitro-and-its-deletion-enhances-msc-efficacy-in-a-model-of-inflammatory-arthritis-in-vivo/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Inflammation is a central feature of rheumatoid arthritis that affects around 1% of the population and can result in disability and morbidity.
The immunomodulatory effects of bone marrow derived mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) has been widely studied and the recent observations that syndecan-3 (SDC3) is selectively pro-inflammatory in the joint led us to hypothesise that SDC3 might play an important role in MSC biology.
MSCs isolated from bone marrow of wild type and Sdc3-/- mice were used to assess immunophenotype, differentiation, adhesion and migration properties and cell signalling pathways.
While both cell types show similar differentiation potential and forward scatter values, the cell complexity in wild type MSCs was significantly higher than in Sdc3-/- cells and was accompanied by lower spread surface area.
Moreover, Sdc3-/- MSCs adhered more rapidly to collagen type I and showed a dramatic increase in AKT phosphorylation, accompanied by a decrease in ERK1/2 phosphorylation compared with control cells.
In a mouse model of antigen-induced inflammatory arthritis, intraarticular injection of Sdc3-/- MSCs yielded enhanced recovery compared to injection of wild type MSCs.
In conclusion, our data suggest that syndecan-3 regulates MSC adhesion and efficacy in inflammatory arthritis, likely via induction of the AKT pathway (Figure 1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:block;&#34; id=&#34;fig:figure1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; alt=&#34;Loss of SCD3 in MSCs causes increased ATK phosphorylation and a reduction in ERK phosphorylation.  (A) representative images of blots used for quantification. SDC3 knockout was confirmed for Sdc3-/- MSCs in each sample (B) Total phosphorylated tyrosine normalised to GAPDH. (C) Phosphorylated AKTSer473 was normalised to total AKT. (D) Phosphorylated ERKThr202/Tyr204 was normalised to total ERK. Quantification was performed using ImageJ.&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: Loss of SCD3 in MSCs causes increased ATK phosphorylation and a reduction in ERK phosphorylation. (A) representative images of blots used for quantification. SDC3 knockout was confirmed for Sdc3-/- MSCs in each sample (B) Total phosphorylated tyrosine normalised to GAPDH. (C) Phosphorylated AKTSer473 was normalised to total AKT. (D) Phosphorylated ERKThr202/Tyr204 was normalised to total ERK. Quantification was performed using ImageJ.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The management of talar osteochondral lesions - Current concepts</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/the-management-of-talar-osteochondral-lesions-current-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/the-management-of-talar-osteochondral-lesions-current-concepts/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/the-management-of-talar-osteochondral-lesions-current-concepts/index.en_files/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A 12-month clinical study. Spontaneous healing of articular cartilage (SHARC study)</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/spontaneous-healing-of-articular-cartilage-sharc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/spontaneous-healing-of-articular-cartilage-sharc/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;When the cartilage in your joint is damaged, it is often thought that it does not heal and would eventually lead to joint degeneration.
However, we have found evidence that in some instances, cartilage can repair itself without surgical intervention.&lt;br /&gt;
We studied this natural healing in patients who had an artificial cartilage defect created in their knees as part of a cell therapy trial.
Biopsies of the regenerated cartilage tissues were taken about 12 months after the defect was created and examined in our lab to determine their quality and whether the tissues returned to their original structure.
What we found showed that although the damaged cartilage did repair itself, it did not return to its normal structure, at least in that timescale.
For instance, collagens are very important molecules in cartilage, and we found that their organisation was different in the naturally repaired cartilage compared to normal.
This information is useful to us in that it may help to understand how we can improve ways of encouraging better repair tissue to form.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human chondrocytes expanded in the Quantum® hollow-fibre bioreactor system</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/human-chondrocytes-expanded-in-the-quantum-hollow-fibre-bioreactor-system-for-the-first-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/human-chondrocytes-expanded-in-the-quantum-hollow-fibre-bioreactor-system-for-the-first-time/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;The Quantum® bioreactor (Fig 9; Terumo BCT) is an automated hollow fibre system, which has an internal surface area of 2.1m&lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(^2\)&lt;/span&gt; (equivalent to 120 T-175 tissue culture flasks), allowing large scale expansion of cells.&lt;br /&gt;
In recently published work we have been using the Quantum® to assess the characteristics of cells from human bone marrow and umbilical cords after culture expansion in the system compared to the standard tissue culture plastic technique (TCP), with the aim of using these cells in cell therapies for example, for cartilage repair.&lt;br /&gt;
In a newly funded ‘Confidence in Concept’ MRC project we have looked to transfer these techniques to cells of cartilage (chondrocytes), in the development of up-scale manufactured allogeneic chondrocyte therapies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far cells from 4 samples obtained from adult donors (undergoing total knee replacements) and 2 samples obtained from juvenile (polydactyl) donors have been cultured in the Quantum® and the results are currently being analysed.
Techniques for chondrocyte growth and harvest using the system are being optimised and further MRC Biomedical Catalyst funded work will ensure GMP compliance of the manufacturing process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The suitability of pre-operative MRI in predicting accurate cartilage defect sizes in cell therapy</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/the-suitability-of-pre-operative-magnetic-resonance-imaging-in-predicting-accurate-cartilage-defect-sizes-for-treatment-with-cell-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/the-suitability-of-pre-operative-magnetic-resonance-imaging-in-predicting-accurate-cartilage-defect-sizes-for-treatment-with-cell-therapy/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Clinicians are given guidance as to appropriate sizes of cartilage defects to treat with cell therapy.
However, estimating the size of a defect using scans such as magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) may in fact differ from the ‘real-life’ situation.
We performed a retrospective study to evaluate the accuracy of MRI scans to predict the size of articular cartilage lesions in the knee and compared them against actual defect sizes recorded surgically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We included 64 patients, all of whom underwent autologous cell implantation (ACI) performed by two different RJAH surgeons (PDG and JBR).
Each patient received a pre-operative MRI approximately 6 weeks prior to cell implantation.
MRIs were analysed by a Consultant radiologist (BT) and a research PhD student (JP) trained by the radiologist to ascertain the full-thickness defect measurement and the total abnormal defect area that they believed would require debridement (removal of damaged/ unhealthy tissue).
At the time of cell implantation, the Consultant orthopaedic surgeon measured the defect sizes pre- and post-debridement.
The post-debridement surgical measurements have been used as the ‘gold standard’ in this study.
All measurements were further assessed according to defect location within the knee (patella, trochlea, medial or lateral femoral condyle (MFC and LFC)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We assessed a total of 92 cartilage defects and, as expected, found them to be significantly smaller pre-debridement than post-debridement when measured during arthroscopy.
To date, from a radiological perspective (BT), MRI scans significantly underestimated the (pre-debridement) defect size but not the total abnormal area (so this was found to be similar and not significantly different to the post-debridement size measured surgically).&lt;br /&gt;
When considering defect location, MRI still significantly underestimated pre-debridement defect sizes on the patella and MFC but not the LFC and trochlea.
Total abnormal area assessment on MRI was not affected by defect location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This preliminary data indicates that measuring only the full-thickness component of a cartilage defect on MRI will significantly underestimate the area to treat for ACI; evaluating the whole abnormal area will provide a more accurate estimate of the actual defect size requiring treatment. This is critical for surgical planning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
