<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rebecca Davis | Oswestry Keele Orthopaedic Research group - OsKOR</title>
    <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/author/rebecca-davis/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://oskor.netlify.app/author/rebecca-davis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Rebecca Davis</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://oskor.netlify.app/media/logo_hu0e35ae0aaba2517cccb2b0d7ca3e2f28_296151_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url>
      <title>Rebecca Davis</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/author/rebecca-davis/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keele courses and conferences</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/events/faculty-pgr-symposium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/events/faculty-pgr-symposium/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Keele courses and conferences&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#pgr-symposium-2022&#34;&gt;PGR Symposium 2022&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#pgr-symposium-2023&#34;&gt;2023&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#pgr-symposium-2024&#34;&gt;2024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#cartilage-symposium-2022&#34;&gt;Cartilage Symposium 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#tissue-microenvironment-2023&#34;&gt;Tissue Microenvironment and Disease Workshop 2023 20-21-Apr-2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#bioreactor-course-2023&#34;&gt;Bioreactor Course, Keele University 21-Mar-2023 - 24 -Mar-2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pgr-symposium-2024&#34;&gt;
PGR Symposium 2024
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PGR Symposium 2024 was held in Keele campus on the 17th and the 18th of June 2024.&lt;br /&gt;
On the 17th of June,Dr Jade Perry gave an excellent career talk title 10 years in 15 minutes, where she explained her journey through research to the audiance, giving tips and advices to current and future PhD students attending the symposium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two final years PhD students Anaïs Makos and Tian Lan gave a 15 minute talk summarizing their thesis and highlighting their findings:&lt;br /&gt;
- Anaïs Makos: Potential biomarkers predicting response to TNF-blockers in Psoriatic Arthritis&lt;br /&gt;
- Tian Lan: Cell therapy for repair of cartilage defects in the ankle - A PhD summary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 18th of June, Larissa Rix participated to the 3-minute thesis and gave us a summary of her PhD project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abi Jones, Henry Barrett, Hollie Wilkinson, Ton Link and Yumna Ladha displayed their academic posters to share their work with all PhD students and supervisors attending the symposium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pgr-symposium-2023&#34;&gt;
PGR Symposium 2023
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PGR Symposium 2023 was help on the 14th of March 2023.&lt;br /&gt;
Anaïs Makos and Rebecca Davies shared their projects with the audience with a 10 minute presentation followed by interesting questions and discussion on their work.
- Anaïs Makos: PARIS study: Psoriatic Arthritis – Resistance to TNF Inhibitor Study&lt;br /&gt;
- Rebecca Davies: Combining cell donors to increase extracellular vesicle yields to meet the demand of treatment for inflammatory arthritis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jessica Fisher-Stokes, Larissa Rix and Tian Lan displayed their academic posters; and Henry Barrett and Hollie Wilkinson displayed their engagement posters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tissue-microenvironment-2023&#34;&gt;
Tissue Microenvironment and Disease Workshop 2023 20-21-Apr-2023
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several members of the group attened a fantastic 2-day workshop at Keele Hall, with some excellent speakers on topics including: Imaging the diseased microenvironment; Data based approaches to microenvironmental analysis; Biological methods in the tumour microenvironment. Our team did brilliantly with Dr Helen McCarthy and Ms Hollie Wilkinson winning poster and oral prizes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bioreactor-course-2023&#34;&gt;
Bioreactor Course, Keele University 21-Mar-2023 - 24-Mar-2023
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drs Charlotte Hulme and Karina Wright organised the 2023 Bioreactors and Growth Environments Workshop. The workshop welcomed over 70 delegates, from the UK, Europe and further afield. Speakers included experts from academia and industry, providing an overview of the basic principles of bioreactor design through to their clinical applications. We had some excellent student engagement in the ‘Design a Bioreactor Challenge’, with the winning group working together to develop a novel bioreactor for assessing tissue engineered tendons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cartilage-symposium-2022&#34;&gt;
Cartilage Symposium 2022
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;group1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 7th and 8th of June 2022 the 12th Oswestry/Keele Cartilage Symposium was held at Keele Hall, organised by Dr Helen McCarthy, Dr Karina Wright, Prof Martyn Snow, Prof Sally Roberts, and Mr Paul Jermin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The international symposium gathered surgeons and scientists from the UK, Ireland, Germany, Switzerland, and USA to talk about the latest research and clinical updates in terms of treatments, biomarkers next generation biological repair and rehabilitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During these two days, speakers focus on “Influencing factors in cartilage repair outcomes”, “Current trends in cartilage repair”, “Next generation biological repair”, “Pain in Osteoarthritis”, and “Biomarkers for monitoring knee diseases and treatments”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;session1.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstracts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Jan Herman Kuiper – ACTIVE, a multicentre RCT of ACI versus other surgical interventions for cartilage defects: five-year results”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Paul Jermin – Autologous blood products with or without platelets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Karina Wright – Proteomic characterization of response to ACI&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Bernhard Tins – Imaging as a biomarker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An early career session was also organised to allow PhD student and post-docs to introduce their projects to experts in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;session2.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstracts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebecca Davies – Umbilical cord mesenchymal stromal cell derived extracellular vesicles match, and perhaps surpass, their parental cell’s ability to treat inflammatory arthritis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tian Lan – Characterisation of mesenchymal stromal cells isolated from autologous bone marrow aspirate concentrates used clinically in the treatment of cartilage defects in the ankle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anaïs Makos – Predicting patients’ response to TNF inhibitors using potential blood biomarkers in Psoriatic Arthritis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Dr Mahid Ahmed (Newcastle) who won the early career presentation award with “A bioprinted high-throughput human 3D osteochondral model for osteoarthritis research”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Picture%202.png&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to all the presenters for being with us and for sharing their hard work to the assembly and thank you to the organisers who did an amazing job hosting the event and providing an opportunity for us to discuss our data with international experts from around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;sponsor.png&#34; width=&#34;80%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pgr-symposium-2022&#34;&gt;
PGR Symposium 2022
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 29th of April was held the Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences 2022 PGR Symposium at Keele University. PhD students from faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences gathered to share their project in the form of 3 minutes presentation (3-minute thesis), 10 minutes presentation and poster presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three PhD students from our department participated to this symposium:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rebecca Davis: “The therapeutic effect of umbilical cord mesenchymal stromal cell extracellular vesicles in inflammatory arthritis”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anaïs makos: “Immune cell profile in patient with Psoriatic Arthritis”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tian Lan: “Characterisation of mesenchymal stromal cells isolated from autologous bone marrow aspirate concentrates used clinically in the treatment of cartilage defects in the ankle”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The oral presentation runner up prize went to Rebecca Davis for her presentation of extracellular vesicles (EV) “The therapeutic effect of umbilical cord mesenchymal stromal cell extracellular vesicles in inflammatory arthritis”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;prize.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Day</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/events/research-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/events/research-day/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#rjah-2022&#34;&gt;Researh day 2022&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#rjah-2023&#34;&gt;2023&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#rjah-2024&#34;&gt;2024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rjah-2024&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;RJAH Research day 2024&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June 2024 was held the 25th annual research day at the RJAH Orthopaedic hospital in Oswestry.
Surgeons, clinicians, researchers and students shared and discusses their work with other professionals. Research day was a great day to enhance collaboraion and discussion between labs and theatres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OSKOR groups presented several project in the science session:
- Dr Charlotte Hulme - Identification of Synovial Fluid Proteins as Candidate Biomarkers of Cartilage Repair Tissue Quality Following Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation&lt;br /&gt;
- Dr Jan Herman Kuiper - Mathematical model of signalling molecule-mediated processes during repair of osteochondral defects after cell therapy
- Dr Jade Perry - Whole-Organ Computed Tomography Score (WOCT) of the Knee
- Ms Larissa Rix - An Investigation into The Patellofemoral Joint: Improving Diagnostics, Prognostics and Cell-Based Therapies&lt;br /&gt;
- Mr Thavisha Ranasinghe - Developing up-scale allogeneic chondrocyte therapies using juvenile donor cartilage&lt;br /&gt;
- Mr Henry Barrett - The potential utility of human regulatory T cell-deriVed ExtRacellular veSicles to control inflammation in rheUmatoid arthritiS (VERSUS)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in the combined science and clinic session:
- Dr Sharon Owen - Preliminary investigation of the potential of ‘old’ drugs for treatment use in adults with Spinal Muscular Atrophy&lt;br /&gt;
- Ms Tian Lan - Cell Therapy for Repair of Cartilage Defects in the Ankle - A PhD summary
- Ms Amaïs Makos - PARIS study - Potential biomarkers to predict response to TNF inhibitors in psoriatic arthritis&lt;br /&gt;
- Ms Hollie Wilkinson - Using nanopore sequencing to diagnose prosthetic joint infections: an update on the methodology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Jan Herman Kuiper won the golden tube and was awareded with the best scientific presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OSKOR group also presented their work in interesting poster:
- Ms Abi Jones
- Mr Tom Link
- Ms Yumna Ladha
- Mr Zaid Maniar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulation to Mr Zaid Maniar who won the best poster presentation of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rjah-2023&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;RJAH Research day 2023&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RJAH held its annual research day on Friday 28th April. The exciting programme saw separate scientific and clinical sessions in the morning and a combined session in the afternoon. OsKOR showcased their recent results with many students, post-docs and group leads presenting their work as oral and poster presentations. We also had a number Keele staff and colleagues joining the day and a highlight was the keynote talk from Dr Dan Tonge, who gave us a fascinating insight on his experiences that have taken him from a wet lab scientist to a bioinformatician. Ms Hollie Wilkinson (1st year PhD student) won the ‘Golden Test Tube’ for best scientific talk, again! And Miss Jessica Fisher-Stokes and Ms Abi Jones shared the best poster prize!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rjah-2022&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;RJAH Research day 2022&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April 2022, surgeons and researchers of the RJAH Orthopaedic Hospital gathered to share their latest developments in term of surgery, treatments and research for the 23rd Research Day. The day began with a Q&amp;amp;A session led by Mr Andrew Roberts, Director of Research and Ms Stacy Keegan, Acting Chief Executive. Scientists and surgeons presented their projects, and a one-hour session was dedicated to poster presentation during lunch time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must thank our judge Dr John Garcia who was also our guest lecturer this year, with his lecture on advances in CAR T cell therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Award for the best scientific poster went to Dr Karina Wright for her poster presentation “Multilevel Modelling of Longitudinal Outcome Data 20 Years Post- Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Award for the best clinical presentation was conferred on Dr Jan Herman Kuiper for his presentation “Autologous chondrocyte implantation in osteochondral defects of the talus: Two to Fourteen Year Follow-up study”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
