<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anaïs Makos | Oswestry Keele Orthopaedic Research group - OsKOR</title>
    <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/author/anais-makos/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://oskor.netlify.app/author/anais-makos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Anaïs Makos</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://oskor.netlify.app/media/logo_hu0e35ae0aaba2517cccb2b0d7ca3e2f28_296151_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url>
      <title>Anaïs Makos</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/author/anais-makos/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>PARIS Study: Potential biomarkers predicting response to TNFi in Psoriatic Arthritis</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/paris-study-potential-biomarkers-predicting-response-to-tnfi-in-psoriatic-arthritis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/paris-study-potential-biomarkers-predicting-response-to-tnfi-in-psoriatic-arthritis/</guid>
      <description>



</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracellular vesicle events</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/events/international-society-extracellular-vesicles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/events/international-society-extracellular-vesicles/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#ukev-2024&#34;&gt;UKEV forum 2024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#isev-2022&#34;&gt;International Society of Extracellular Vesicles 2022&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#isev-2023&#34;&gt;2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#ev-cons-2022&#34;&gt;EV consultation in Vietnam&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ukev-2024&#34;&gt;
UKEV forum 2024
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;ukev-24.png&#34; width=&#34;80%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our group had the pleasure of participating in the UKEV Forum 2024, a premier event focused on extracellular vesicle
(EV) research and innovation. The forum provided a fantastic opportunity to present our latest work, connect with
leading companies, and explore exciting new technologies in the EV field.
We showcased two posters, highlighting recent advancements in our research, which received great interest from the
community. The event also offered a platform for valuable networking. We engaged with ONI, who performed some imaging
for us, and nanoFCM, whose cutting-edge nanoparticle analysis technology we plan to implement in our work next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;isev-2023&#34;&gt;
International Society of Extracellular Vesicles 2023
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;isev-2023.png&#34; width=&#34;80%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ms Rebecca Davies recently attended the International Society for Extracellular Vesicle’s Annual Meeting (ISEV2023) in Seattle, Washington, as part of her final year PhD on mesenchymal stromal cell extracellular vesicles (MSC EVs). Here, she got a chance to see the forefront of EV research, new EV technologies and discuss upcoming regulations with scientists in the field. She also presented my own work in the poster session, giving her a chance to discuss my PhD with like-minded scientists to gain their opinion and expertise. She said that “Overall, it was a valuable experience and one that will greatly enhance my approach to EV research.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;isev-2022&#34;&gt;
International Society of Extracellular Vesicles 2022
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;group.jpg&#34; width=&#34;80%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May 2022, Dr Oksana Kehoe and Becky Davies (3rd Year PhD student) attended the International
Society for Extracellular Vesicles Annual Meeting (ISEV2022) at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eventscribe.net/2022/ISEV2022/&#34;&gt;Centre des Congrès of Lyon, France&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The annual meeting offered an unparalleled opportunity to learn from, teach, and network with,
leading and emerging experts in EV research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This event featured the best in vesicle science, covering all aspects of fundamental,
translational, and clinical research, disseminating cutting-edge developments in EV research.
ISEV2022 brought together scientists from academic, clinics, and industry, who have a common
goal of understanding EVs and applying this knowledge for societal and economic benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Becky Davies is the winner of the ISEV2022 Scholarship and was selected for oral presentation with her abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/the-therapeutic-effect-of-umbilical-cord-mesenchymal-stromal-cell-extracellular-vesicles-in-inflammatory-arthritis/&#34;&gt;Rebecca Davies, Mairead Hyland, Claire Mennan, Karina Wright, Mark Platt, Oksana Kehoe ’The therapeutic effect of umbilical cord mesenchymal stromal cell extracellular vesicles in inflammatory arthritis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Fig1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;60%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Fig2.jpg&#34; width=&#34;60%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ev-cons-2022&#34;&gt;
EV consultation in Vietnam
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summer 2022, a member of the OsKoR research team, Rebecca Davies, travelled to Hanoi, Vietnam where she acted as a consultant for &lt;a href=&#34;&amp;#39;https://www.vinmec.com/en/&amp;#39;&#34;&gt;the Vinmec Healthcare System&lt;/a&gt;. Here, our knowledge of mesenchymal stromal cell extracellular vesicles (MSC EVs) was used to assist the Vinmec team on enrichment and characterisation of their GMP grade MSC EVs for future use in animal studies and clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;ev-cons.jpg&#34; width=&#34;60%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keele courses and conferences</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/events/faculty-pgr-symposium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/events/faculty-pgr-symposium/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Keele courses and conferences&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#pgr-symposium-2022&#34;&gt;PGR Symposium 2022&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#pgr-symposium-2023&#34;&gt;2023&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#pgr-symposium-2024&#34;&gt;2024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#cartilage-symposium-2022&#34;&gt;Cartilage Symposium 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#tissue-microenvironment-2023&#34;&gt;Tissue Microenvironment and Disease Workshop 2023 20-21-Apr-2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#bioreactor-course-2023&#34;&gt;Bioreactor Course, Keele University 21-Mar-2023 - 24 -Mar-2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pgr-symposium-2024&#34;&gt;
PGR Symposium 2024
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PGR Symposium 2024 was held in Keele campus on the 17th and the 18th of June 2024.&lt;br /&gt;
On the 17th of June,Dr Jade Perry gave an excellent career talk title 10 years in 15 minutes, where she explained her journey through research to the audiance, giving tips and advices to current and future PhD students attending the symposium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two final years PhD students Anaïs Makos and Tian Lan gave a 15 minute talk summarizing their thesis and highlighting their findings:&lt;br /&gt;
- Anaïs Makos: Potential biomarkers predicting response to TNF-blockers in Psoriatic Arthritis&lt;br /&gt;
- Tian Lan: Cell therapy for repair of cartilage defects in the ankle - A PhD summary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 18th of June, Larissa Rix participated to the 3-minute thesis and gave us a summary of her PhD project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abi Jones, Henry Barrett, Hollie Wilkinson, Ton Link and Yumna Ladha displayed their academic posters to share their work with all PhD students and supervisors attending the symposium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pgr-symposium-2023&#34;&gt;
PGR Symposium 2023
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PGR Symposium 2023 was help on the 14th of March 2023.&lt;br /&gt;
Anaïs Makos and Rebecca Davies shared their projects with the audience with a 10 minute presentation followed by interesting questions and discussion on their work.
- Anaïs Makos: PARIS study: Psoriatic Arthritis – Resistance to TNF Inhibitor Study&lt;br /&gt;
- Rebecca Davies: Combining cell donors to increase extracellular vesicle yields to meet the demand of treatment for inflammatory arthritis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jessica Fisher-Stokes, Larissa Rix and Tian Lan displayed their academic posters; and Henry Barrett and Hollie Wilkinson displayed their engagement posters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tissue-microenvironment-2023&#34;&gt;
Tissue Microenvironment and Disease Workshop 2023 20-21-Apr-2023
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several members of the group attened a fantastic 2-day workshop at Keele Hall, with some excellent speakers on topics including: Imaging the diseased microenvironment; Data based approaches to microenvironmental analysis; Biological methods in the tumour microenvironment. Our team did brilliantly with Dr Helen McCarthy and Ms Hollie Wilkinson winning poster and oral prizes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bioreactor-course-2023&#34;&gt;
Bioreactor Course, Keele University 21-Mar-2023 - 24-Mar-2023
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drs Charlotte Hulme and Karina Wright organised the 2023 Bioreactors and Growth Environments Workshop. The workshop welcomed over 70 delegates, from the UK, Europe and further afield. Speakers included experts from academia and industry, providing an overview of the basic principles of bioreactor design through to their clinical applications. We had some excellent student engagement in the ‘Design a Bioreactor Challenge’, with the winning group working together to develop a novel bioreactor for assessing tissue engineered tendons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cartilage-symposium-2022&#34;&gt;
Cartilage Symposium 2022
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;group1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 7th and 8th of June 2022 the 12th Oswestry/Keele Cartilage Symposium was held at Keele Hall, organised by Dr Helen McCarthy, Dr Karina Wright, Prof Martyn Snow, Prof Sally Roberts, and Mr Paul Jermin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The international symposium gathered surgeons and scientists from the UK, Ireland, Germany, Switzerland, and USA to talk about the latest research and clinical updates in terms of treatments, biomarkers next generation biological repair and rehabilitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During these two days, speakers focus on “Influencing factors in cartilage repair outcomes”, “Current trends in cartilage repair”, “Next generation biological repair”, “Pain in Osteoarthritis”, and “Biomarkers for monitoring knee diseases and treatments”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;session1.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstracts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Jan Herman Kuiper – ACTIVE, a multicentre RCT of ACI versus other surgical interventions for cartilage defects: five-year results”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Paul Jermin – Autologous blood products with or without platelets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Karina Wright – Proteomic characterization of response to ACI&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Bernhard Tins – Imaging as a biomarker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An early career session was also organised to allow PhD student and post-docs to introduce their projects to experts in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;session2.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstracts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebecca Davies – Umbilical cord mesenchymal stromal cell derived extracellular vesicles match, and perhaps surpass, their parental cell’s ability to treat inflammatory arthritis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tian Lan – Characterisation of mesenchymal stromal cells isolated from autologous bone marrow aspirate concentrates used clinically in the treatment of cartilage defects in the ankle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anaïs Makos – Predicting patients’ response to TNF inhibitors using potential blood biomarkers in Psoriatic Arthritis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Dr Mahid Ahmed (Newcastle) who won the early career presentation award with “A bioprinted high-throughput human 3D osteochondral model for osteoarthritis research”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Picture%202.png&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to all the presenters for being with us and for sharing their hard work to the assembly and thank you to the organisers who did an amazing job hosting the event and providing an opportunity for us to discuss our data with international experts from around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;sponsor.png&#34; width=&#34;80%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pgr-symposium-2022&#34;&gt;
PGR Symposium 2022
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 29th of April was held the Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences 2022 PGR Symposium at Keele University. PhD students from faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences gathered to share their project in the form of 3 minutes presentation (3-minute thesis), 10 minutes presentation and poster presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three PhD students from our department participated to this symposium:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rebecca Davis: “The therapeutic effect of umbilical cord mesenchymal stromal cell extracellular vesicles in inflammatory arthritis”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anaïs makos: “Immune cell profile in patient with Psoriatic Arthritis”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tian Lan: “Characterisation of mesenchymal stromal cells isolated from autologous bone marrow aspirate concentrates used clinically in the treatment of cartilage defects in the ankle”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The oral presentation runner up prize went to Rebecca Davis for her presentation of extracellular vesicles (EV) “The therapeutic effect of umbilical cord mesenchymal stromal cell extracellular vesicles in inflammatory arthritis”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;prize.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Day</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/events/research-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/events/research-day/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#rjah-2022&#34;&gt;Researh day 2022&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#rjah-2023&#34;&gt;2023&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#rjah-2024&#34;&gt;2024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rjah-2024&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;RJAH Research day 2024&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June 2024 was held the 25th annual research day at the RJAH Orthopaedic hospital in Oswestry.
Surgeons, clinicians, researchers and students shared and discusses their work with other professionals. Research day was a great day to enhance collaboraion and discussion between labs and theatres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OSKOR groups presented several project in the science session:
- Dr Charlotte Hulme - Identification of Synovial Fluid Proteins as Candidate Biomarkers of Cartilage Repair Tissue Quality Following Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation&lt;br /&gt;
- Dr Jan Herman Kuiper - Mathematical model of signalling molecule-mediated processes during repair of osteochondral defects after cell therapy
- Dr Jade Perry - Whole-Organ Computed Tomography Score (WOCT) of the Knee
- Ms Larissa Rix - An Investigation into The Patellofemoral Joint: Improving Diagnostics, Prognostics and Cell-Based Therapies&lt;br /&gt;
- Mr Thavisha Ranasinghe - Developing up-scale allogeneic chondrocyte therapies using juvenile donor cartilage&lt;br /&gt;
- Mr Henry Barrett - The potential utility of human regulatory T cell-deriVed ExtRacellular veSicles to control inflammation in rheUmatoid arthritiS (VERSUS)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in the combined science and clinic session:
- Dr Sharon Owen - Preliminary investigation of the potential of ‘old’ drugs for treatment use in adults with Spinal Muscular Atrophy&lt;br /&gt;
- Ms Tian Lan - Cell Therapy for Repair of Cartilage Defects in the Ankle - A PhD summary
- Ms Amaïs Makos - PARIS study - Potential biomarkers to predict response to TNF inhibitors in psoriatic arthritis&lt;br /&gt;
- Ms Hollie Wilkinson - Using nanopore sequencing to diagnose prosthetic joint infections: an update on the methodology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Jan Herman Kuiper won the golden tube and was awareded with the best scientific presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OSKOR group also presented their work in interesting poster:
- Ms Abi Jones
- Mr Tom Link
- Ms Yumna Ladha
- Mr Zaid Maniar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulation to Mr Zaid Maniar who won the best poster presentation of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rjah-2023&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;RJAH Research day 2023&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RJAH held its annual research day on Friday 28th April. The exciting programme saw separate scientific and clinical sessions in the morning and a combined session in the afternoon. OsKOR showcased their recent results with many students, post-docs and group leads presenting their work as oral and poster presentations. We also had a number Keele staff and colleagues joining the day and a highlight was the keynote talk from Dr Dan Tonge, who gave us a fascinating insight on his experiences that have taken him from a wet lab scientist to a bioinformatician. Ms Hollie Wilkinson (1st year PhD student) won the ‘Golden Test Tube’ for best scientific talk, again! And Miss Jessica Fisher-Stokes and Ms Abi Jones shared the best poster prize!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rjah-2022&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;RJAH Research day 2022&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April 2022, surgeons and researchers of the RJAH Orthopaedic Hospital gathered to share their latest developments in term of surgery, treatments and research for the 23rd Research Day. The day began with a Q&amp;amp;A session led by Mr Andrew Roberts, Director of Research and Ms Stacy Keegan, Acting Chief Executive. Scientists and surgeons presented their projects, and a one-hour session was dedicated to poster presentation during lunch time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must thank our judge Dr John Garcia who was also our guest lecturer this year, with his lecture on advances in CAR T cell therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Award for the best scientific poster went to Dr Karina Wright for her poster presentation “Multilevel Modelling of Longitudinal Outcome Data 20 Years Post- Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Award for the best clinical presentation was conferred on Dr Jan Herman Kuiper for his presentation “Autologous chondrocyte implantation in osteochondral defects of the talus: Two to Fourteen Year Follow-up study”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psoriatic arthritis: review of potential biomarkers predicting response to TNF inhibitors</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/psoriatic-arthritis-review-of-potential-biomarkers-predicting-response-to-tnf-inhibitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/psoriatic-arthritis-review-of-potential-biomarkers-predicting-response-to-tnf-inhibitors/</guid>
      <description>


</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biomarkers for the PARIS study: Psoriatic Arthritis - Resistance to TNF Inhibitor Study</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/paris-psoriatic-arthritis-resistance-to-tnf-inhibitor-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/paris-psoriatic-arthritis-resistance-to-tnf-inhibitor-study/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Psoriatic arthritis (PsA) is a chronic immune-mediated inflammatory disease
and patients suffer from joint and spinal pain because of immune cell
infiltration and expansion in skin and synovium. These cells release a large
panel of pro inflammatory factors responsible for the inflammation, as
cytokines and chemokines. We can cite for instance Tumor Necrosis Factor &lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(α\)&lt;/span&gt;
(TNF&lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(α\)&lt;/span&gt;), Interleukin (IL)-17, IL-23 and IL-1&lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(β\)&lt;/span&gt; released by Peripheral
Blood Mononuclear Cells (PBMC) such as CD4+ and CD8+ T cells, neutrophils and
macrophages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PsA occurs in 30% of people with psoriasis. It diminishes considerably the
quality of life of patients and serious desabiliting effects are present on
the peripheral joints, spine, tendon insertion and fingers. PsA accounts for
20% of referrals to the early arthritis clinic and early recognition and
intervention is crucial to patient outcome. Currently, diagnosis of PsA is
not optimal because there are no precise tests available to detect or
recognize the disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No curative treatments are available for PsA. Non Steroidal Anti-Inflammatory
drugs (NSAID) are used as first approach for topical therapy for psoriasis
and to reduce pain; the next step is administration of Disease-Modifying
Anti-Rheumatic Drugs (DMARDs) alone, and then in combination; and finally,
biologic drugs targeting specific cytokines and signaling pathways, such as
TNF&lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(α\)&lt;/span&gt; inhibitors or IL-17 inhibitors, are administrated if patients fail to
respond NSAID and DMARDs. However, at least 40% of patients with PsA have
only a partial response or fail to respond to biologics.
The aim of the PSAPS study is to investigate whether blood inflammatory
markers can predict if patients with PsA will respond or not to TNF&lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(α\)&lt;/span&gt;
inhibitors, and consequently to help choosing the optimal biologic therapy
for patients, individually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First literature research has highlighted several promising inflammatory
factors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Human Serum Albumin and its receptor FcRn (Neonatal Fc Receptor)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alarmins, such as S100 family members and HMGB1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced Glycation End-products (AGEs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lymphotoxin α, the second ligand to TNF Receptor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrays allowing the detection of hundreds of pro inflammatory markers can
also be used to analyze serum of patients at a large scale, and IL-17 pathway
will be screen in detail to understand why some patients respond to IL-17
inhibitors while they do not respond to TNF&lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(α\)&lt;/span&gt;-inhibitors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
