<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events | Oswestry Keele Orthopaedic Research group - OsKOR</title>
    <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/category/events/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://oskor.netlify.app/category/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Events</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://oskor.netlify.app/media/logo_hu0e35ae0aaba2517cccb2b0d7ca3e2f28_296151_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url>
      <title>Events</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/category/events/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charity events</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/events/snowpaedic-challenge-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/events/snowpaedic-challenge-2022/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#walk-2023&#34;&gt;Sponsored walk - 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#snowpaedic-2022&#34;&gt;Snowpaedic challende - 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#marathon-2021&#34;&gt;London Marathon - 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;walk-2023&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Sponsord walk at the Llyn Brenig Lake&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;walk.jpeg&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 16th of September 2023, researchers and students of the OSKOR groups participated in a walk around the beautiful Llyn Brenig Lake, and raised money to improve research in Duchenne Muscular Dystrophy.
Duchenne Muscular Dystrophy (DMD) is a genetic disorder marked by the gradual weakening and degeneration of muscles. It ranks among the most prevalent and severe types of muscular dystrophy. This rare disease is typically diagnosed in early childhood and results in a shortened lifespan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;snowpaedic-2022&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Snowpaedic challenge&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;pictures.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Saturday the 10th of September 2022, our research team participated to the annual Snowpaedic challenge, a sponsored walk organized by the Orthopaedic Institute Charity to support research and education at the RJAH Orthopaedic Hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, the Orthopaedic Institute Charity raised fund to support a research study into the Charcot-Marie-Tooth(CMT) disease, a hereditary motor and sensitive neuropathy of the Peripheral Nervous System (PNS). The disease is characterized by progressive loss of muscle tissue and touch sensation across diverse parts of the body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Orthopaedic Institute Charity has supported research and educational project at the RJAH Hospital for over 50 years to benefit patients with musculo-skeletal conditions such as arthritis, rheumatism and spinal cord injuries. It also support joint replacement and cell therapy for repair and healing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;marathon-2021&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;London Marathon to support the RJAH Orthopaedic Charity&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;marathon.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our reserachers based at the RJAH Orthopaedic hopital took part in the Virgin London Marathon on the 3rd of October 2021. Dr Jade Perry and Ms Emily Storey managed to raise over £2,500 for the RJAH Orthopaedic hosptial charitable fund.
Running this marathon was a huge challenge, and donations will be used for the benefit of the patients and staff at the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EULAR congress</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/events/eular-congress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/events/eular-congress/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;The European Alliance od Association for Rheumatology (EULAR) hold a congress in Europe every year to share new discovery and advancement in rheumatic disease pathogenesis, diagnosis, prognosis and treatments. The congress encourage collaboration between scientists and consultants and organises networking events to stimulate discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#eular-2023&#34;&gt;EULAR congress - 2023&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#eular-2024&#34;&gt;2024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;eular-2024&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;EULAR congress 2024&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;picture2.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Oksana Kehoe, Ms Anaïs Makos and Dr Roshan Amarasena attended the EULAR congress 2024 in Vienna where their abstract “PARIS Study: Potential biomarkers predicting response to TNFi in Psoriatic Arthritis” was accepted for publication and for poster view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;eular-2023&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;EULAR congress 2023&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;picture1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Oksana Kehoe, Ms Anaïs Makos and Dr Roshan Amarasena attended the EULAR congress 2023 in Milan where their abstract “Potential biomarkers to predict TNF inhibitor outcome in psoriatic arthritis” was accepted for publication. They heard scientific and clinical talks from international speakers and were particularly proud to attend Prof Sally Roberts’ talk who had been invited to talk about cell therapy for cartilage repair and osteoarthritis. Dr Amarasena and Dr Askari, consultant rheumatologists at the Robert Jones and Agnes Hunt (RJAH) Orthopaedic hospital were also in attendance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracellular vesicle events</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/events/international-society-extracellular-vesicles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/events/international-society-extracellular-vesicles/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#ukev-2024&#34;&gt;UKEV forum 2024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#isev-2022&#34;&gt;International Society of Extracellular Vesicles 2022&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#isev-2023&#34;&gt;2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#ev-cons-2022&#34;&gt;EV consultation in Vietnam&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ukev-2024&#34;&gt;
UKEV forum 2024
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;ukev-24.png&#34; width=&#34;80%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our group had the pleasure of participating in the UKEV Forum 2024, a premier event focused on extracellular vesicle
(EV) research and innovation. The forum provided a fantastic opportunity to present our latest work, connect with
leading companies, and explore exciting new technologies in the EV field.
We showcased two posters, highlighting recent advancements in our research, which received great interest from the
community. The event also offered a platform for valuable networking. We engaged with ONI, who performed some imaging
for us, and nanoFCM, whose cutting-edge nanoparticle analysis technology we plan to implement in our work next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;isev-2023&#34;&gt;
International Society of Extracellular Vesicles 2023
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;isev-2023.png&#34; width=&#34;80%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ms Rebecca Davies recently attended the International Society for Extracellular Vesicle’s Annual Meeting (ISEV2023) in Seattle, Washington, as part of her final year PhD on mesenchymal stromal cell extracellular vesicles (MSC EVs). Here, she got a chance to see the forefront of EV research, new EV technologies and discuss upcoming regulations with scientists in the field. She also presented my own work in the poster session, giving her a chance to discuss my PhD with like-minded scientists to gain their opinion and expertise. She said that “Overall, it was a valuable experience and one that will greatly enhance my approach to EV research.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;isev-2022&#34;&gt;
International Society of Extracellular Vesicles 2022
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;group.jpg&#34; width=&#34;80%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May 2022, Dr Oksana Kehoe and Becky Davies (3rd Year PhD student) attended the International
Society for Extracellular Vesicles Annual Meeting (ISEV2022) at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eventscribe.net/2022/ISEV2022/&#34;&gt;Centre des Congrès of Lyon, France&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The annual meeting offered an unparalleled opportunity to learn from, teach, and network with,
leading and emerging experts in EV research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This event featured the best in vesicle science, covering all aspects of fundamental,
translational, and clinical research, disseminating cutting-edge developments in EV research.
ISEV2022 brought together scientists from academic, clinics, and industry, who have a common
goal of understanding EVs and applying this knowledge for societal and economic benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Becky Davies is the winner of the ISEV2022 Scholarship and was selected for oral presentation with her abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/the-therapeutic-effect-of-umbilical-cord-mesenchymal-stromal-cell-extracellular-vesicles-in-inflammatory-arthritis/&#34;&gt;Rebecca Davies, Mairead Hyland, Claire Mennan, Karina Wright, Mark Platt, Oksana Kehoe ’The therapeutic effect of umbilical cord mesenchymal stromal cell extracellular vesicles in inflammatory arthritis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Fig1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;60%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Fig2.jpg&#34; width=&#34;60%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ev-cons-2022&#34;&gt;
EV consultation in Vietnam
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summer 2022, a member of the OsKoR research team, Rebecca Davies, travelled to Hanoi, Vietnam where she acted as a consultant for &lt;a href=&#34;&amp;#39;https://www.vinmec.com/en/&amp;#39;&#34;&gt;the Vinmec Healthcare System&lt;/a&gt;. Here, our knowledge of mesenchymal stromal cell extracellular vesicles (MSC EVs) was used to assist the Vinmec team on enrichment and characterisation of their GMP grade MSC EVs for future use in animal studies and clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;ev-cons.jpg&#34; width=&#34;60%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICRS</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/events/icrs-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/events/icrs-2022/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#focus-icrs&#34;&gt;ICRS Focus Meeting: Allografts &amp;amp; Synthetics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#icrs-2022&#34;&gt;ICRS 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;focus-icrs&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;ICRS Focus Meeting: Allografts &amp;amp; Synthetics (Nice, France) - April 27-29 2023&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;icrs-jade.png&#34; width=&#34;80%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Jade Perry was awarded a prestigious travel scholarship to attend the Allograft and Synthetics focus meeting in Nice. The exciting program explored the knee joint as a whole organ, focusing not only on the treatment of articular cartilage but also other issues such as meniscal allografts and malalignment. The conference effectively brought together everything from diagnostics to imaging, to conservative and surgical treatments, as well as basic science (biological approaches). Due to the international nature of the conference, it was a great opportunity to hear from a diverse range of speakers and network with experts from across the globe.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;icrs-2022&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;ICRS - April 2022&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April, 11 members of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rjah.nhs.uk/&#34;&gt;RJAH Orthopaedic hospital&lt;/a&gt;, inclusive of surgeons and researchers, attended the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cartilage.org/event/icrs-2021-16th-world-congress-2/&#34;&gt;ICRS world congress conference&lt;/a&gt; in the
bustling city of Berlin, Germany. The meeting offered an opportunity to listen to
thought provoking talks varying from surgery techniques, current and emerging cell
therapies, to industry talks and application of products. Armed with 7 talks and 8
posters between us, we showcased some of our outstanding research to members of the
conference and were met with positive, encouraging responses. A very proud moment of
the conference was witnessing one of the special members of our team, Professor Sally
Roberts, achieving the lifetime recognition award. As well as Dr Timothy Hopkins
awarded a poster prize for his research ‘initial development of a synovial joint on a
chip model’. Alongside the conference, there were many social events and networking
opportunities to get involved in, including a next generation ‘happy hour’, in which
new scientists and experienced minds came together to gain new knowledge and
partnerships. Whilst not forgetting to put a little time aside to explore the
historical sights of Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List of abstracts (oral presentations):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Martyn Snow - &lt;a href=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/the-importance-of-aci-position-in-the-context-of-other-methods-unmet-needs-in-larger-defects/&#34;&gt;“The Importance of ACI-Position in the context of other methods/unmet needs in larger defects”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Martyn Snow - &lt;a href=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/review-of-outcomes-surrounding-meniscal-allograft-transplantation/&#34;&gt;“Review of Outcomes Surrounding Meniscal Allograft Transplantation”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Karina Wright, Jingsong Wang, Peter Denis Gallacher, Zhanfeng Cui, Sally Roberts - &lt;a href=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/phenotypic-characterisation-of-regional-human-meniscus-progenitor-cells/&#34;&gt;“Phenotypic Characterisation of Regional Human Meniscus Progenitor Cells”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Karina Wright, Lauren Tierney, Mike Williams, Mateus Harrington, Jan Herman Kuiper, Peter Denis Gallacher, Paul Jermin, Martyn Snow, Sally Roberts - &lt;a href=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/multilevel-modelling-of-longitudinal-outcome-data-20-years-post-autologous-chondrocyte-implantation/&#34;&gt;“Multilevel Modelling of Longitudinal Outcome Data 20 Years Post-Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jade Perry, Claire Mennan, Paul Cool, Helen McCarthy, Karin Newell, Timothy Hopkins, Charlotte Hulme, Karina Wright, Frances Henson, Sally Roberts - &lt;a href=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/human-umbilical-cord-derived-mesenchymal-stromal-cells-reduce-radiographic-osteoarthritis-in-an-ovine-model/&#34;&gt;“Human Umbilical Cord-Derived Mesenchymal Stromal Cells Reduce Radiographic Osteoarthritis in an Ovine Model”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List of abstracts (posters):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Karina Wright, Jingsong Wang, Sally Roberts - &lt;a href=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/a-novel-tissue-engineering-approach-for-meniscus-replacement-evaluated-utilising-an-ovine-explant-model/&#34;&gt;“A novel Tissue Engineering Approach for Meniscus Replacement Evaluated Utilising an Ovine Explant Model”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Charlotte Hulme, John Garcia, Robert Freeman, Nigel Kiely, Derfel Williams, Jonathan Wright, Karina Wright - &lt;a href=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/juvenile-chondrocytes-novel-alternatives-for-allogeneic-cell-therapy/&#34;&gt;“Juvenile Chondrocytes: Novel Alternatives for Allogeneic Cell Therapy?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Charlotte Hulme, Sophie Bailey, Timothy Hopkins, Helen McCarthy, Ilyas Khan, Martyn Snow, Karina Wright - &lt;a href=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/assessing-allogeneic-chondroprogenitor-manufacture-in-xeno-free-and-serum-free-media/&#34;&gt;“Assessing Allogeneic Chondroprogenitor Manufacture in Xeno-free and Serum-free Media”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tian Lan, Karina Wright, Nilesh Makwana, Andrew Bing, Charlotte Hulme, Helen McCarthy - &lt;a href=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/characterisation-of-mesenchymal-stromal-cells-isolated-from-bone-marrow-aspirate-concentrate/&#34;&gt;“Characterisation of mesenchymal stromal cells isolated from bone marrow aspirate concentrate”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clare Thompson, Timothy Hopkins, Karina Wright, Martin Knight - &lt;a href=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/development-of-a-human-synovial-joint-on-a-chip-model/&#34;&gt;“Development of a Human Synovial Joint-on-a-Chip Model”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Timothy Hopkins, Karina Wright, Sally Roberts, Paul Jermin, Peter Denis Gallacher, Jan Herman Kuiper - &lt;a href=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/macroscopic-assessment-of-articular-cartilage-quality-correlates-with-histological-assessment-of-subchondral-bone-health/&#34;&gt;“Macroscopic Assessment of Articular Cartilage Quality Correlates with Histological Assessment of Subchondral Bone Health”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Timothy Hopkins, Karina Wright, John Garcia, Jade Perry, Paul Jermin, Peter Denis Gallacher, Sally Roberts - &lt;a href=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/severity-of-synovitis-and-macrophage-phenotypes-in-knee-cartilage-defect-and-osteoarthritis-cohorts/&#34;&gt;“Severity of Synovitis and Macrophage Phenotypes in Knee Cartilage Defect and Osteoarthritis Cohorts”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jan Herman Kuiper, Adam Devany, Nilesh Makwana, Anup Pradhan, Caroline Lever, Patrick Laing, Sally Roberts, James Richardson - &lt;a href=&#34;https://oskor.netlify.app/publication/autologous-chondrocyte-implantation-in-osteochondral-defects-of-the-talus-two-to-fourteen-year-follow-up-study/&#34;&gt;“Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation in Osteochondral Defects of the Talus: Two to Fourteen Year Follow-up Study”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special acknowledgement to Professor Sally Roberts who received a Lifetime recognition award, and to Dr Timothy Hopkins who received the poster award.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;awards_icrs.png&#34; width=&#34;80%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keele courses and conferences</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/events/faculty-pgr-symposium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/events/faculty-pgr-symposium/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Keele courses and conferences&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#pgr-symposium-2022&#34;&gt;PGR Symposium 2022&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#pgr-symposium-2023&#34;&gt;2023&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#pgr-symposium-2024&#34;&gt;2024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#cartilage-symposium-2022&#34;&gt;Cartilage Symposium 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#tissue-microenvironment-2023&#34;&gt;Tissue Microenvironment and Disease Workshop 2023 20-21-Apr-2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#bioreactor-course-2023&#34;&gt;Bioreactor Course, Keele University 21-Mar-2023 - 24 -Mar-2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pgr-symposium-2024&#34;&gt;
PGR Symposium 2024
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PGR Symposium 2024 was held in Keele campus on the 17th and the 18th of June 2024.&lt;br /&gt;
On the 17th of June,Dr Jade Perry gave an excellent career talk title 10 years in 15 minutes, where she explained her journey through research to the audiance, giving tips and advices to current and future PhD students attending the symposium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two final years PhD students Anaïs Makos and Tian Lan gave a 15 minute talk summarizing their thesis and highlighting their findings:&lt;br /&gt;
- Anaïs Makos: Potential biomarkers predicting response to TNF-blockers in Psoriatic Arthritis&lt;br /&gt;
- Tian Lan: Cell therapy for repair of cartilage defects in the ankle - A PhD summary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 18th of June, Larissa Rix participated to the 3-minute thesis and gave us a summary of her PhD project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abi Jones, Henry Barrett, Hollie Wilkinson, Ton Link and Yumna Ladha displayed their academic posters to share their work with all PhD students and supervisors attending the symposium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pgr-symposium-2023&#34;&gt;
PGR Symposium 2023
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PGR Symposium 2023 was help on the 14th of March 2023.&lt;br /&gt;
Anaïs Makos and Rebecca Davies shared their projects with the audience with a 10 minute presentation followed by interesting questions and discussion on their work.
- Anaïs Makos: PARIS study: Psoriatic Arthritis – Resistance to TNF Inhibitor Study&lt;br /&gt;
- Rebecca Davies: Combining cell donors to increase extracellular vesicle yields to meet the demand of treatment for inflammatory arthritis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jessica Fisher-Stokes, Larissa Rix and Tian Lan displayed their academic posters; and Henry Barrett and Hollie Wilkinson displayed their engagement posters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tissue-microenvironment-2023&#34;&gt;
Tissue Microenvironment and Disease Workshop 2023 20-21-Apr-2023
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several members of the group attened a fantastic 2-day workshop at Keele Hall, with some excellent speakers on topics including: Imaging the diseased microenvironment; Data based approaches to microenvironmental analysis; Biological methods in the tumour microenvironment. Our team did brilliantly with Dr Helen McCarthy and Ms Hollie Wilkinson winning poster and oral prizes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bioreactor-course-2023&#34;&gt;
Bioreactor Course, Keele University 21-Mar-2023 - 24-Mar-2023
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drs Charlotte Hulme and Karina Wright organised the 2023 Bioreactors and Growth Environments Workshop. The workshop welcomed over 70 delegates, from the UK, Europe and further afield. Speakers included experts from academia and industry, providing an overview of the basic principles of bioreactor design through to their clinical applications. We had some excellent student engagement in the ‘Design a Bioreactor Challenge’, with the winning group working together to develop a novel bioreactor for assessing tissue engineered tendons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cartilage-symposium-2022&#34;&gt;
Cartilage Symposium 2022
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;group1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 7th and 8th of June 2022 the 12th Oswestry/Keele Cartilage Symposium was held at Keele Hall, organised by Dr Helen McCarthy, Dr Karina Wright, Prof Martyn Snow, Prof Sally Roberts, and Mr Paul Jermin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The international symposium gathered surgeons and scientists from the UK, Ireland, Germany, Switzerland, and USA to talk about the latest research and clinical updates in terms of treatments, biomarkers next generation biological repair and rehabilitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During these two days, speakers focus on “Influencing factors in cartilage repair outcomes”, “Current trends in cartilage repair”, “Next generation biological repair”, “Pain in Osteoarthritis”, and “Biomarkers for monitoring knee diseases and treatments”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;session1.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstracts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Jan Herman Kuiper – ACTIVE, a multicentre RCT of ACI versus other surgical interventions for cartilage defects: five-year results”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Paul Jermin – Autologous blood products with or without platelets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Karina Wright – Proteomic characterization of response to ACI&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Bernhard Tins – Imaging as a biomarker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An early career session was also organised to allow PhD student and post-docs to introduce their projects to experts in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;session2.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstracts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebecca Davies – Umbilical cord mesenchymal stromal cell derived extracellular vesicles match, and perhaps surpass, their parental cell’s ability to treat inflammatory arthritis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tian Lan – Characterisation of mesenchymal stromal cells isolated from autologous bone marrow aspirate concentrates used clinically in the treatment of cartilage defects in the ankle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anaïs Makos – Predicting patients’ response to TNF inhibitors using potential blood biomarkers in Psoriatic Arthritis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Dr Mahid Ahmed (Newcastle) who won the early career presentation award with “A bioprinted high-throughput human 3D osteochondral model for osteoarthritis research”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Picture%202.png&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to all the presenters for being with us and for sharing their hard work to the assembly and thank you to the organisers who did an amazing job hosting the event and providing an opportunity for us to discuss our data with international experts from around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;sponsor.png&#34; width=&#34;80%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pgr-symposium-2022&#34;&gt;
PGR Symposium 2022
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 29th of April was held the Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences 2022 PGR Symposium at Keele University. PhD students from faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences gathered to share their project in the form of 3 minutes presentation (3-minute thesis), 10 minutes presentation and poster presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three PhD students from our department participated to this symposium:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rebecca Davis: “The therapeutic effect of umbilical cord mesenchymal stromal cell extracellular vesicles in inflammatory arthritis”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anaïs makos: “Immune cell profile in patient with Psoriatic Arthritis”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tian Lan: “Characterisation of mesenchymal stromal cells isolated from autologous bone marrow aspirate concentrates used clinically in the treatment of cartilage defects in the ankle”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The oral presentation runner up prize went to Rebecca Davis for her presentation of extracellular vesicles (EV) “The therapeutic effect of umbilical cord mesenchymal stromal cell extracellular vesicles in inflammatory arthritis”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;prize.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outreach event</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/events/outreach-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/events/outreach-event/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Dr Jade Perry (Post doctorate researcher), Rebecca Davies and Emily Storey (3rd Year
PhD students) of the Oswestry and Keele Orthopaedic Research group (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rjah.nhs.uk/&#34;&gt;RJAH Orthopaedic Hospital&lt;/a&gt;) recently visited the Marches School in Oswestry.
In preparation for choosing their GCSE subjects, they talked to Year 9 students about
science. This included how science is used in all careers, not just those in the
science sector, and how their career paths led us to where they are now. To highlight
their work in the Orthopaedic Hospital, they informed students of various roles
scientists have there, from research to patient diagnostics, and their personal
experiences being at forefront of the COVID-19 pandemic to perform routine testing.
They hoped that this encouraged students to consider the benefits of science in
general, broaden their knowledge about science-orientated careers, and convince them
that science can be an interesting career choice that benefits the general public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;outreach.png&#34; width=&#34;496&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin: auto;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Day</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/events/research-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/events/research-day/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#rjah-2022&#34;&gt;Researh day 2022&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#rjah-2023&#34;&gt;2023&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;#rjah-2024&#34;&gt;2024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rjah-2024&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;RJAH Research day 2024&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June 2024 was held the 25th annual research day at the RJAH Orthopaedic hospital in Oswestry.
Surgeons, clinicians, researchers and students shared and discusses their work with other professionals. Research day was a great day to enhance collaboraion and discussion between labs and theatres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OSKOR groups presented several project in the science session:
- Dr Charlotte Hulme - Identification of Synovial Fluid Proteins as Candidate Biomarkers of Cartilage Repair Tissue Quality Following Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation&lt;br /&gt;
- Dr Jan Herman Kuiper - Mathematical model of signalling molecule-mediated processes during repair of osteochondral defects after cell therapy
- Dr Jade Perry - Whole-Organ Computed Tomography Score (WOCT) of the Knee
- Ms Larissa Rix - An Investigation into The Patellofemoral Joint: Improving Diagnostics, Prognostics and Cell-Based Therapies&lt;br /&gt;
- Mr Thavisha Ranasinghe - Developing up-scale allogeneic chondrocyte therapies using juvenile donor cartilage&lt;br /&gt;
- Mr Henry Barrett - The potential utility of human regulatory T cell-deriVed ExtRacellular veSicles to control inflammation in rheUmatoid arthritiS (VERSUS)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in the combined science and clinic session:
- Dr Sharon Owen - Preliminary investigation of the potential of ‘old’ drugs for treatment use in adults with Spinal Muscular Atrophy&lt;br /&gt;
- Ms Tian Lan - Cell Therapy for Repair of Cartilage Defects in the Ankle - A PhD summary
- Ms Amaïs Makos - PARIS study - Potential biomarkers to predict response to TNF inhibitors in psoriatic arthritis&lt;br /&gt;
- Ms Hollie Wilkinson - Using nanopore sequencing to diagnose prosthetic joint infections: an update on the methodology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Jan Herman Kuiper won the golden tube and was awareded with the best scientific presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OSKOR group also presented their work in interesting poster:
- Ms Abi Jones
- Mr Tom Link
- Ms Yumna Ladha
- Mr Zaid Maniar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulation to Mr Zaid Maniar who won the best poster presentation of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rjah-2023&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;RJAH Research day 2023&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RJAH held its annual research day on Friday 28th April. The exciting programme saw separate scientific and clinical sessions in the morning and a combined session in the afternoon. OsKOR showcased their recent results with many students, post-docs and group leads presenting their work as oral and poster presentations. We also had a number Keele staff and colleagues joining the day and a highlight was the keynote talk from Dr Dan Tonge, who gave us a fascinating insight on his experiences that have taken him from a wet lab scientist to a bioinformatician. Ms Hollie Wilkinson (1st year PhD student) won the ‘Golden Test Tube’ for best scientific talk, again! And Miss Jessica Fisher-Stokes and Ms Abi Jones shared the best poster prize!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rjah-2022&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;RJAH Research day 2022&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April 2022, surgeons and researchers of the RJAH Orthopaedic Hospital gathered to share their latest developments in term of surgery, treatments and research for the 23rd Research Day. The day began with a Q&amp;amp;A session led by Mr Andrew Roberts, Director of Research and Ms Stacy Keegan, Acting Chief Executive. Scientists and surgeons presented their projects, and a one-hour session was dedicated to poster presentation during lunch time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must thank our judge Dr John Garcia who was also our guest lecturer this year, with his lecture on advances in CAR T cell therapy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Award for the best scientific poster went to Dr Karina Wright for her poster presentation “Multilevel Modelling of Longitudinal Outcome Data 20 Years Post- Autologous Chondrocyte Implantation”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Award for the best clinical presentation was conferred on Dr Jan Herman Kuiper for his presentation “Autologous chondrocyte implantation in osteochondral defects of the talus: Two to Fourteen Year Follow-up study”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
