<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oksana Keohe | Oswestry Keele Orthopaedic Research group - OsKOR</title>
    <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/author/oksana-keohe/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://oskor.netlify.app/author/oksana-keohe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Oksana Keohe</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://oskor.netlify.app/media/logo_hu0e35ae0aaba2517cccb2b0d7ca3e2f28_296151_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url>
      <title>Oksana Keohe</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/author/oksana-keohe/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biomarkers for the PARIS study: Psoriatic Arthritis - Resistance to TNF Inhibitor Study</title>
      <link>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/paris-psoriatic-arthritis-resistance-to-tnf-inhibitor-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://oskor.netlify.app/project/paris-psoriatic-arthritis-resistance-to-tnf-inhibitor-study/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Psoriatic arthritis (PsA) is a chronic immune-mediated inflammatory disease
and patients suffer from joint and spinal pain because of immune cell
infiltration and expansion in skin and synovium. These cells release a large
panel of pro inflammatory factors responsible for the inflammation, as
cytokines and chemokines. We can cite for instance Tumor Necrosis Factor &lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(α\)&lt;/span&gt;
(TNF&lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(α\)&lt;/span&gt;), Interleukin (IL)-17, IL-23 and IL-1&lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(β\)&lt;/span&gt; released by Peripheral
Blood Mononuclear Cells (PBMC) such as CD4+ and CD8+ T cells, neutrophils and
macrophages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PsA occurs in 30% of people with psoriasis. It diminishes considerably the
quality of life of patients and serious desabiliting effects are present on
the peripheral joints, spine, tendon insertion and fingers. PsA accounts for
20% of referrals to the early arthritis clinic and early recognition and
intervention is crucial to patient outcome. Currently, diagnosis of PsA is
not optimal because there are no precise tests available to detect or
recognize the disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No curative treatments are available for PsA. Non Steroidal Anti-Inflammatory
drugs (NSAID) are used as first approach for topical therapy for psoriasis
and to reduce pain; the next step is administration of Disease-Modifying
Anti-Rheumatic Drugs (DMARDs) alone, and then in combination; and finally,
biologic drugs targeting specific cytokines and signaling pathways, such as
TNF&lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(α\)&lt;/span&gt; inhibitors or IL-17 inhibitors, are administrated if patients fail to
respond NSAID and DMARDs. However, at least 40% of patients with PsA have
only a partial response or fail to respond to biologics.
The aim of the PSAPS study is to investigate whether blood inflammatory
markers can predict if patients with PsA will respond or not to TNF&lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(α\)&lt;/span&gt;
inhibitors, and consequently to help choosing the optimal biologic therapy
for patients, individually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First literature research has highlighted several promising inflammatory
factors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Human Serum Albumin and its receptor FcRn (Neonatal Fc Receptor)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alarmins, such as S100 family members and HMGB1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced Glycation End-products (AGEs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lymphotoxin α, the second ligand to TNF Receptor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrays allowing the detection of hundreds of pro inflammatory markers can
also be used to analyze serum of patients at a large scale, and IL-17 pathway
will be screen in detail to understand why some patients respond to IL-17
inhibitors while they do not respond to TNF&lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(α\)&lt;/span&gt;-inhibitors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
